一條狗的使命2
在這樣的日子里
On days like this,
我覺得自己是世上最幸運的狗
I feel like the luckiest dog in the world.
陽光撫背
I got the sun on my back.
清風拂面
I got the wind in my face.
還能坐在這輛
I get to ride in this car
車窗總是放下的車里
where the windows are always rolled down.
我叫貝利
My name is Bailey.
很享受微風徐來的感覺吧  小伙子
You enjoying the breeze, boy?
-我愛我的男孩  伊森  -狗老大
- I love my boy Ethan. - Boss Dog.
-我也愛我的女孩漢娜  -狗老大
- And I love my girl Hannah, too. - Boss Dog.
人老大
Boss Man.
我活過很多次
I've lived a lot of lives,
尿過很多東西
and I've peed on a lot of stuff.
但有件事我一直搞不明白
There is one thing I've never been able to figure out, though:
這里為什么總是這么癢
Why does it always itch right here?
寶寶可以過來了
Baby can come up.
寶寶可以過來這邊了
Baby can come up here.
我得去了
That's my cue.
我干完活就去廚房找你
I'll meet you in the kitchen after I do the chores.
跟我一樣老態龍鐘了嗎  狗老大
You as creaky as me, Boss Dog?
走吧
Let's go.
拜托  早晨的味道最好了
Come on. Mornings had the best smells.
當然了  我們得干活
Sure, we had to do our chores...
走吧  貝利
Come on, Bailey.
但每次結束時我都能吃一個雞蛋
but it always ended with an egg.
爽
Yeah.
不是吧
Seriously?
伙計
Hey, buddy.
覺得自己寶刀未老嗎  狗老大
Still think you got one in you, Boss Dog?
好吧
Okay.
準備好了嗎
You ready?
生來就準備好了
Born ready.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
上
Go!
干得漂亮  狗老大
Way to go, Boss Dog.
越來越力不從心了
That isn't getting any easier.
寶刀未老啊  狗老大
You still got it, Boss Dog.
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
好孩子
Good boy.
來吧  我們進屋
Come on, let's go to the house.
來吧  伙計  來吧
Come on, buddy. Come on.
來吧
Come on.
來吧  培根  來吧  培根
Come on, bacon. Come on, bacon.
不是培根  但也能吃
It's not bacon, but I'll take it.
早上好
Morning.
-媽媽  你好  -你好
- Hi, Mommy. - Hi.
早上好  格洛麗亞
Morning, Gloria.
漢娜  她什么時候醒的
What time did she wake up, Hannah?
當時沒看時間
Wasn't looking at the clock.
但不要緊
Doesn't matter, though.
我們和小孫女玩得很開心
We're having fun with our granddaughter.
漢娜曾有一個叫亨利的兒子
Hannah used to have a boy named Henry.
他把格洛麗亞帶到了我們家
He brought Gloria into our pack.
一直喂她吃松餅  她就要變成小胖妞了
We keep feeding her pancakes, she's gonna get chubby.
也許這次她會給我點吃的
Maybe this time she'll give me a treat.
沒有吃的  好吧
No? No treat? Okay.
我還以為就是要把小寶寶喂得胖乎乎的
I thought little babies were supposed to be chubby.
伊森  噓
Ethan, shh.
漢娜最近經常說"噓"
Hannah made that "shh" sound a lot lately.
-這是誰  -爸爸
- Who's that? - Daddy.
爸爸  我覺得她遺傳了亨利的眼睛
Daddy. You know, I think she has Henry's eyes.
亨利離開了家  再也沒有回來
Henry went away and never came back.
漢娜為此整天以淚洗面
Hannah cried a lot.
我整天舔她的臉
I licked her face a lot.
真希望兒子還活著
I wish my son was alive
見見他可愛的女兒
to see his adorable daughter.
她丟地上  我吃掉
She drops it, I eat it.
-這是我們的約定  -掉到地上了
- That's our deal. - It fell.
橙色  紫色
Orange. Purple.
格洛麗亞喜歡把吃的放在臉上
Gloria liked to wear food on her face.
-但不是好吃的  -你好
- But not good food. - Hello?
一條惡心的狗剛剛在舔我的臉
A... a gross dog just licked my face.
不  被困在農場就會發生這樣的事
No, no, that's-that's how it goes when you're stuck on a farm.
CJ  你要去哪
CJ, where are you going?
我們應該在這玩
We're supposed to play here.
在芝加哥遇到什么事了
What's happening in Chicago?
一五一十地告訴我  一邊去
Tell me everything. Go away.
你們要出去玩嗎
Are you guys going out?
我看見馬馬了
I see the horsey.
不  別進去
No, don't go in there.
CJ  停下
CJ, stop.
他很害怕
He's scary.
吁  伙計  吁
Whoa, boy. Whoa.
伊森氣喘吁吁的樣子
From the way he was breathing,
能看出來他很害怕
I knew Ethan was scared.
不知道  我感覺...
I don't know. I feel like...
你在做什么
What are you doing?
等會打回給你
Hey, let me call you back.
CJ剛剛跑到萊納斯那里去了
CJ just got in with Linus.
過來
Hey, come here.
格洛麗亞  她有可能會受傷
She could have been hurt, Gloria.
貝利救了她
Bailey saved her.
恕我直言
Let me get this straight.
它是電視上的那種英雄狗嗎
It's one of those hero dogs you see on TV?
它叫貝利
Its name is Bailey.
我喜歡聽我的男孩伊森叫我的名字
I love when my boy Ethan says my name.
進屋吧
Go inside.
我知道你做了什么  狗老大
I know what you did, Boss Dog.
走吧
Come on.
我不知道格洛麗亞是從哪找來這個寶寶的
I don't know where Gloria found this baby,
但她是個很棒的新成員
but it is a great addition.
CJ是個聰明  充滿好奇心的孩子
CJ is smart and curious.
我們得照看好她
We just have to keep an eye on her.
我就轉身了兩秒
Well, I turned my back for two seconds.
更像是兩年吧
More like two years.
CJ
CJ.
-吃一口  CJ  -不吃
- Come on, CJ. - No.
-克拉里蒂·瓊  -奶奶  奶奶
- Clarity. Clarity June. - Nana, Nana.
媽媽在這  你能叫聲媽媽嗎
Mama's here now. Can you say "Mama"?
奶奶  奶奶
Nana, Nana.
好吧
All right.
克拉里蒂·瓊  這不好玩
Clarity June, that is not funny.
有點好玩
It's kind of funny.
為什么從來沒有人往我臉上涂吃的
Why doesn't anyone ever wipe food on my face?
經歷了興奮刺激的一天后
After all the excitement of the day,
我得在大水盆里降降溫
I had to cool off in the big water bowl.
你知道那是什么
You know what that is.
玩得開心嗎
You having fun yet?
爺...
Grand...
爺爺  天哪
Grandpa. Oh... oh, my goodness.
我就讓你們帶她幾個小時
I-I leave her with you for a couple hours,
你們就讓克拉里蒂和骯臟的狗一起洗澡
and you have Clarity bathing with a filthy dog?
格洛麗亞終于想和我們一起玩了
Finally, Gloria wants to play.
他們只是在一起玩水
Well, they're just playing.
好了  出去  狗
All right, get-get out. Get out, dog.
拜托
Come on.
他們只是在一起玩
They're just having fun.
這樣吧
You know what?
別擔心  寶貝  媽媽來了
Don't worry, honey. Mommy's here.
好了  沒事的
Come on. It's okay.
我知道你想讓我做什么了
I get what you want me to do.
這就是我不喜歡狗的原因
This is why I don't like dogs.
也許你是想用鼻子拱我屁股吧
Maybe you wanted to stick your nose in my butt?
格洛麗亞年紀輕輕就成了寡婦
Gloria is just so young to be a widow.
亨利出車禍的時候她已經懷胎八月了
Eight months pregnant when Henry was in that car accident.
我知道  親愛的  我知道
I know, honey. I know.
漢娜  但她的母性本能哪去了
But, Hannah, where's her maternal instinct?
格洛麗亞只是想搞清楚
Gloria's just trying to figure out
她和CJ要如何謀生
how she's gonna make a life for herself and CJ.
但她拿到了亨利的保險理賠金
But she's got Henry's insurance settlement.
那筆錢已經存起來留給CJ上大學用了
Well, that money's been set aside for CJ's college fund.
養大兩個孩子的是你  不是我
You're the one that raised two kids, not me.
所以你不擔心的話
So, if you're not worried about it,
我就不擔心
I'm not worried about it.
她們如果不在這里  我就會擔心
I'd be worried if they weren't here.
-是啊  -爽
- Yeah. - Yeah.
往上點  就是這里
Up, up, up. There we go.
沒錯  就在中間
Yeah, right in the middle.
往下滑  往下滑  舒服
Now slide it down. Slide it down. Yeah.
我覺得我們三個可以提供
Between the three of us, I think we can
這個小女孩需要的愛
give that little girl the love that she needs.
疼
Ouch!
-那是什么  -怎么了
- What is that? - What?
是個腫塊
It's a lump.
大腫塊
Big lump.
別再戳我肚子上的那一塊了
Please stop poking that spot on my belly.
我要帶他去看獸醫
I'm gonna take him to the vet.
-好  -怎么回事
- Yeah. - What's going on?
伙計  你好  貝利
Hey, buddy. Hi, Bailey.
不知怎地  伊森總是知道我什么時候想坐車
Somehow, Ethan always knows when I want to take a car ride.
狗老大
Boss Dog.
好好休息  好嗎  伙計
I want you to stay put, okay, buddy?
德布醫生說應該盡量讓你過得舒適
Dr. Deb said we should just keep you comfortable.
我一個人干活就行了
I can handle all the chores.
我經歷過壞日子  也經歷過好日子
I had bad days, and I had good days.
-今天就是個好日子  -我也是
- Today was a good day. - Well, me, too.
我終于接到游輪打來的電話了
Well, I finally got a call from the, um... the cruise line.
格洛麗亞老是對著自己的手說話
Gloria spent a lot of time talking to her hand.
他們的馬車廳需要一位歌手
And they needed a singer for their Stagecoach Lounge.
-狗狗  狗狗  -我知道
- Doggy, doggy, doggy. - I know.
杯子里什么都沒有
There's nothing in that cup.
你有給我倒一杯嗎
Did you make me a cup?
-奶奶  給你  -謝謝
- Here, Nana. - Thank you.
很適合我  不是嗎
Well, it's perfect for me, right?
-好喝  -那么好喝嗎
- Delicious. - That delicious?
等等  杯子里有東西嗎
Wait, there was something in that cup?
是啊  他們選了一個
Yeah, they went with a singer who, uh,
不用帶小孩的歌手
does not have a toddler.
我說不好
I don't know.
也許我該回芝加哥
Maybe I should come back to Chicago.
-還要嗎  -嗯  但我不知道還能做什么
- More? - Yeah, but I don't really know what more I can do.
哄她睡覺太難了
Getting her to go down for her nap took forever.
格洛麗亞  是這樣
You know, Gloria...
如果你想追求自己的事業
if-if you want to pursue your career,
我們可以幫你照顧克拉里蒂
you could leave Clarity here with us.
你覺得我是個壞媽媽嗎
You think I'm a bad mother?
-什么  -格洛麗亞
- What? - Gloria...
不  我不是這個意思
No, that's not what I'm saying.
你想奪走我的孩子嗎
Are you trying to take my-my baby from me?
這個孩子就是我的一切
'Cause my baby is all I have.
格洛麗亞  這是個很好的提議
Gloria, she's making you an incredible offer.
我知道你們為什么要這么做
I know what this is about.
你們想要亨利的理賠金
You want Henry's settlement.
我早就知道你們想要這筆錢
I-I-I knew you wanted that money
這樣你們就可以修這個破農場了
so you can fix this crumbling farm.
這個農場不破
This farm is not crumbling.
伊森很生氣
Ethan was mad.
我很久沒聽過他用這種語氣說話了
I hadn't heard him talk like that in a long time.
這件事和錢無關
It has nothing to do with the money.
是為了給CJ一個溫暖的家
It has to do with providing a loving home for CJ.
漢娜  我是她的媽媽
Well, Hannah, I am her mother.
所以我去哪里  哪里就是她的家
So, wherever I am, that is her home.
而且很明顯  這里不歡迎我
And okay, wow, obviously, I'm not welcome here.
這里永遠歡迎你
You are always welcome here.
這樣你就可以每天告訴我
So you can keep telling me all the things
我又做錯了什么嗎
I'm doing wrong every single day?
不了  謝謝  我現在不需要這些
No, thank you. It's actually not what I need right now.
那CJ呢  她的需要怎么辦呢
Well, what about CJ? What about what she needs?
你想過嗎
Do you ever think about that?
有人想過我需要什么嗎
Does anyone ever think about what I need?!
家庭里出問題了
There was trouble in the pack.
肯定是有人吃了格洛麗亞的食物
Somebody must have eaten Gloria's food.
格洛麗亞  請別走
Gloria, please don't leave.
我們談談  我們可以想辦法
Let's talk about this. We can work it out.
不管要怎么做  拜托  我們可以想辦法
Whatever it takes. Please, we can work this out.
你好像還是不懂  她是我的孩子  不是你的
You don't seem to understand. She's my baby, not yours.
伊森  我們該怎么辦
Ethan, what are we gonna do?
格洛麗亞
Gloria.
漢娜如此悲傷
Such sadness from Hannah.
-奶奶  -我愛你
- Nana. - I Love you.
她的孩子不再出現后  她也曾這么悲傷
Sad like she was after her boy stopped coming around.
聽著  我們想給你些錢
Listen, we want you to have some money.
不了  謝謝
No, thanks.
是給CJ的  你就不能收下嗎
It's for CJ. Would you just take it?
安頓好了記得告訴我們
And let us know where you wind up.
你至少該做到這點
It's the least you could do.
格洛麗亞
Gloria.
再見  CJ
Bye-bye, CJ!
愛你
Love you!
我想幫漢娜和伊森去追車  但是
I wanted to chase the car for Hannah and Ethan, but...
但是我真的沒有力氣
but I just didn't have the energy.
我知道
I know.
我想吃東西讓伊森開心
I wanted to eat to make Ethan happy,
但我一點也不餓
but I wasn't hungry anymore.
CJ離開后這里變得非常安靜
It was really quiet after CJ left.
她會跟我們聯系的
She'll get in touch with us.
最終會的
Eventually.
密歇根的天氣有點冷
It's a little cool out there here in Michigan,
今天還是穿暖和點吧
so you might want to dress warm today.
I Can Love You Like That - John Michael Montgomery
? 你喜歡浪漫電影  從不會忘記 ?
♪ You like romantic movies, you never will forget... ♪
我愛這首歌
I love this song.
我也是
I do, too.
我們別浪費這首歌
Let's not waste this song.
來吧
Come here.
來吧  快點  快
Come here. Come on, come on.
? 你不必再等待 ?
♪ You don't have to wait no more ♪
你總是能讓我感覺好起來
You always make me feel better.
? 我會那樣地愛你 ?
♪ I can love you like that ♪
? 讓你成為我的全世界 ?
♪ I would make you my world... ♪
好吧  好吧
Okay. Okay.
我很累  但我會做這個動作
I'm tired, but I'll do it.
看看你
Look at you.
寶刀未老啊
You still got it.
-貝利  -貝利
- Bailey. - Bailey!
是我  好了
That's me. Okay.
好了  伙計  她有主了
All right, buddy, she's taken.
? 如果你給我機會 ?
♪ If you give me a chance ♪
? 我會那樣地愛你 ?
♪ I can love you like that ♪
德布醫生
Dr. Deb.
我出來看到他躺在這里
I came out here and found him laying here.
他非常痛苦
He's in a lot of pain.
我想是時候了
I think it's time.
你已經盡你所能了
You've done everything you could for him.
你想再跟他說幾句嗎
Do you want a moment?
貝利
Bailey.
貝利  貝利  貝利
Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
我的好孩子
You're my good boy.
我們一起度過了那么多好時光  對嗎
We had such good times together, didn't we?
你為了我做了那么多
You've done so much for me.
也許下一次  你回來的時候
You think maybe next time you... you come back,
可以去找CJ  你覺得呢
you can come back for CJ, you think?
她需要你  就像我以前需要你一樣
She needs you like I needed you.
你可以保護她
You can protect her.
你可以讓她開心  就像你讓我開心一樣
And you make her feel happy like you made me feel happy.
我聽不懂這些話語
I didn't understand all the words,
但不知怎地  我明白伊森的意思
but somehow, I knew what Ethan meant.
-準備好了嗎  伊森  -好了
- Are you ready, Ethan? - Yeah.
-好了伙計  來吧  -好了
- All right, champ. Here we go. - Yeah.
-好孩子  -你不會再痛苦了
- Good boy. - You're not gonna hurt anymore.
我以前經歷過這個
I remember this from before.
稍微刺痛一下
A tiny sting...
然后所有痛苦都化為虛無
and then my pain melted away.
好了  狗老大  好了  伙計
Yeah, Boss Dog. Yeah, bud.
誰是狗老大
Who's the Boss Dog, hmm?
你是狗老大嗎
You the Boss Dog?
我愛你  貝利
I love you, Bailey.
貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利
Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
所有痛苦都消失了
All my pain was gone.
我到了一個神奇的地方
I was in this place, and it was wonderful.
伊森給了我新的使命
Ethan gave me a new purpose.
我要保護CJ
I was going to protect CJ.
在找到她之前我絕不會停下
And I would never stop looking until I found her.
我又變成了小狗
I was a puppy again.
有媽媽和兄弟姐妹
I had a mother and brothers and sisters.
為什么媽媽的乳頭永遠少一個呢
Why are there always seven puppies and six nipples?
別擔心  狗媽媽
Don't you worry, mama dog.
你的小寶貝  每一個我都會幫他們找到好家庭
I'm finding good homes for every single one of your cuties.
但是這次總感覺差了點什么
But it felt like something was missing this time.
我看看
Let's see.
我有耳朵  很長的那種
I have ears, pretty long ones.
我有尾巴  我有鼻子
I have a tail. I have a snout.
不知道我有沒有...
I wonder if I have a...
沒有  這次我是女孩
Nope. I'm a girl this time.
又變成小狗我好開心
It was so great being a puppy again.
我可以玩呀玩呀玩
I got to play and play and-and play.
還有條老狗  他叫丘吉爾先生
There was an old dog named Mr. Churchill.
他可有意思了
He was a lot of fun.
他們太難管了  對吧  丘吉爾先生
They're a real handful, eh, Mr. Churchill?
一個接一個  人們領走了我的兄弟姐妹
One by one, people took my brothers and sisters away.
最后剩下的是我最喜歡的弟弟
All that was left was my favorite brother.
我叫莫莉  他叫洛奇
I was called Molly, and he was called Rocky.
然后有一天  最糟糕的事情發生了
Then, one day, the worst thing happened.
洛奇也要走了
Rocky was going away.
那我還能跟誰一起玩呢
Who was I gonna play with?
你們兩個在一起看著很配
You look perfect together.
那個女孩
That girl.
那個女孩很特別
There's something about that girl.
我聞到了熟悉的氣味
I smell something familiar.
聞上去像是...
It smells like...
CJ
CJ!
我記得我的使命  CJ就是我的使命
I remember my purpose! CJ is my purpose!
我不能讓她離開
I can't let her get away.
我來了  CJ
I'm coming, CJ!
我不能讓伊森失望
I can't let Ethan down.
必須到CJ身邊去
Got to get to CJ.
我能行
I got this.
我能行  我能行  我能行
I got this. I got this. I got this.
我不行
I don't got this.
你和洛奇這么合拍  我很高興
I'm so happy you and Rocky are a good match.
他已經是我的最好的朋友了
He's already my best friend.
我來了  CJ
I'm coming, CJ!
這棟房子的柵欄太多了
This house has too many fences.
CJ  是我
CJ, it's me!
我來保護你了
I-I'm here to protect you.
瘋狗
Psycho puppy.
CJ長成巨大的寶寶了
CJ was a gigantic baby now.
這條小狗瘋了
This puppy is insane.
這是莫莉
That's Molly.
她和弟弟形影不離
She and her brother are inseparable.
你家能考慮兩條一起收養嗎
Would your family consider adopting both of them?
我來說
I got this.
我還是見好就收吧
Think I better get out of here
免得連一條都養不了
before they change their minds about getting one dog.
鹽  牛奶
Salt, milk.
-漢堡  -那你呢
- Hamburger. - How about you?
你父母會同意讓你養狗嗎
Do you think your parents would let you have a puppy?
我媽媽確實很喜歡狗
My mom does love dogs.
是嗎
She does?
我還是閉嘴吧
I'm gonna stop talking.
我知道該怎么做  我帶莫莉回家
I know what to do. I'll take Molly home,
我媽媽會愛上她  然后她會打給你
my mom will go crazy for her, and then she can call you.
-好吧  -好吧
- Well... - Well...
-噓  -漢娜以前也總是發出"噓"聲
- Shh. - Ah, that's the same "shh" sound Hannah always made.
我一直沒明白是什么意思
I never know what it means.
克拉里蒂  是你嗎
Clarity, is that you?
媽媽
Mom.
那個聲音  是格洛麗亞
That voice. It was Gloria.
你有沒有  你有沒有挪動那個
Did you, um... did you move that box
裝有我的錄音樣帶的箱子
that had my demos in it?
-沒碰過  -我遇到了一個
- Didn't touch it. - So, I met a, um...
一個制作人  他非常想聽聽我的音樂
this, like... a producer that really wants to hear my music.
我得做作業了
Got to do homework!
-你的新家  -好了  CJ
- Your new home. - Okay, CJ,
你沒什么好怕的
you've got nothing to fear.
我來保護你  有貓
I'm here to protect you. Oh, cat!
莫莉  不
Molly, no!
莫莉  莫莉
Molly! Molly!
不  不  不
No, no! No!
-好極了  你也喜歡玩追趕游戲  -不
- Great. You love playing chase, too. - No!
停下
Stop!
別動我的作業
Not my homework!
不  莫莉
No, Molly!
莫莉  不  莫莉
Molly, no. Molly!
不
No!
不  莫莉  不
No, Molly, no!
慢點  莫莉
Slow down, Molly!
拜托  莫莉
Please. Molly.
這下面有好多可以啃的東西
There's so much to chew on under here.
太棒了
Oh, yeah!
真好玩
That was fun.
-下一個游戲是什么  -莫莉
- What's the next game? - Molly.
你是條破壞狗  沒錯
You're Destructo-Dog. Yes, you are.
我喜歡我的新床
I love my new bed.
-你睡在哪  -好了  莫莉
- Where do you sleep? - Here you go, Molly.
希爾達說你基本懂得外出大小便了
Hilda said you were mostly house-trained,
我暫時在這里放條毛巾  以防萬一
so for now, I'll just put a towel down here, just in case.
想尿的時候  誰也攔不住
When you got to go, you got to go.
不  莫莉  不行
No, Molly, no.
CJ  我得跟你談談
CJ, I need to talk to you.
在換衣服
Changing.
人呢  這門怎么鎖上了
Hello? Why's this door locked?
CJ
CJ.
-快點  -稍等
- Come on. - Just a minute.
我沒玩過這個游戲
Yeah, don't know this game.
不過我可以試試
I will give it a try.
剛剛動靜怎么那么大
What's... what is with all this noise?
CJ  這里簡直像是轟炸現場
CJ, it looks like a bomb went off in here.
我在重新整理房間
I've been doing a little rearranging.
臭死了  你不能把窗戶打開嗎
It smells terrible. Will you at least open a window?
我喜歡你這身  是新買的嗎
I love your outfit. Is it new?
你真的很喜歡嗎
Do you love, love, love it?
我今晚要約會
I have a date tonight.
你要出門
You're going out!
他怎么樣  人好嗎
How is he? Is he nice?
CJ  男人一開始看上去都很好
Well, CJ, they always start out nice.
那你今晚能自己解決晚飯嗎
So can you figure out your-your dinner tonight?
又來
Again?
對
Yeah.
我想把你藏起來可能比我想的要難
I think hiding you might be a little more difficult than I thought.
寶貝  準備好了嗎
Hey, babe. You ready?
我們走吧
Let's go.
CJ
CJ?
-準備好了嗎  -我該說什么
- Are you ready? - What do I say?
問一個問題  然后接著打給她
Ask a question and keep calling back.
不準笑  我得進入角色
Don't laugh. I need to get into character.
- CJ去哪了  -祝我好運吧
- Where did CJ go? - Wish me luck.
是你啊  CJ
Oh, hi, CJ.
喂
Hello?
喂  是希爾達嗎
Hello? Is this Hilda?
我是格洛麗亞·米切爾
This is Gloria Mitchell.
你好  我正在等你打電話來
Hello. I've been expecting your call.
太好了  太好了
Wonderful, wonderful.
今天我女兒克拉里蒂把那條可愛的狗帶回家了
My daughter, Clarity, brought home that sweet dog today.
我們簡直太喜歡她了
We just adore her to pieces.
克拉里蒂  親愛的  我正在跟希爾達說
Clarity, honey, I'm telling Hilda
我們有多愛莫莉
how much we love Molly.
你能稍等一下嗎
Can you hold on for a sec?
時間掐的真準  特倫特
Right on time, Trent.
喂  我是特倫特
Hello? This is Trent.
我應該給洛奇喂多少狗糧
How much kibble should I feed Rocky?
半杯  我得掛了
Half a cup. Uh, I got to go.
正如我所說  我們很想把她留下來
As I was saying, we'd love to be her forever home.
你能稍等一下嗎
Can you hold on for a sec?
干得漂亮  特倫特
Good work, Trent.
量杯是美制還是英制的
Is that half a cup U.S. or half a cup imperial?
半杯就行
It's just half a cup.
或許我應該以重量計算
Maybe I should do it by weight.
你想怎么算就怎么算
Y-You can do it however you want.
我得掛了
I got to go.
-不好意思  總是打斷...  -而現在
- I'm sorry for all of these... - And right now,
我正望著我們巨大的
I'm looking out at our ginormously huge,
后院草坪  莫莉和克拉里蒂
grassy backyard, and Molly and Clarity
正在上面打滾
are rolling all around.
我的天  抱歉稍等一下
Oh, dear. Um, can you excuse me?
我忘記告訴你了
I forgot to tell you,
我給洛奇取了個中間名
I gave Rocky a middle name.
我現在真的很忙
I'm really busy at the moment.
克里夫  懂嗎
Cliff. Get it?
洛奇·克里夫[懸崖峭壁]  挺有趣吧
Rocky Cliff. Pretty funny, right?
我之后再打給你好嗎
Can I call you later about this?
別太晚  因為我明天還得上學
Don't call me too late, because I have school tomorrow
要早點上床睡覺
and I need to go to bed early.
聽起來一切都非常棒
Sounds like a wonderful situation.
我很開心你們相處融洽
I'm so glad it worked out.
那我就不打擾你了  謝謝你
Well, then I'll leave you alone, and thank you.
-怎么樣  -我們成功了
- Well? - We did it!
太刺激了
That was amazing.
我以前從沒做過壞事
I've never done anything bad before.
謝謝  謝謝  謝謝
Thank you, thank you, thank you!
我也會大叫
I can make noise, too!
來吧  快  洛奇
Let's go. Come on, Rocky.
擊掌
High five.
我愛你  狗狗
I love you, girl.
我們成功了
We did it!
我知道自己的使命是保護CJ
I knew my purpose was to protect CJ,
但既然她安然無恙
but since she was safe,
我覺得和洛奇玩耍也是可以的
I thought it was okay to play with Rocky.
洛奇咬爛了家里所有的拖鞋
Rocky destroyed all the slippers in the house.
我爸爸一直在用普通話罵人
My dad's doing a lot of swearing in Mandarin.
我昨晚帶莫莉出去了兩次
I had to take Molly out twice last night.
她還是在我床上尿尿了
She still peed on my bed.
我簡直不敢相信你設法藏了一條小瘋狗
I can't believe you managed to hide a crazy puppy
哪怕只藏了一天
for even one day.
我們應該一起訓練他們
We should train them together.
你們要去小狗學校了
You guys are going to puppy school.
-洛奇  別這樣  -不  莫莉  不
- Rocky, come on! - No! No, Molly, no!
他們怎么走得這么慢
Why are they walking so slow?
洛奇  慢點
Rocky, slow down!
坐下  坐下
Sit. Sit.
坐下
Sit.
好吧  那你站著吧
Okay, then stand.
乖狗狗
Good dog.
不  你必須得有權威
No, you have to be the authority.
看我的  學著點
Watch and learn.
趴下  趴下
Lie down. Lie down.
-趴下  -我等你想個更好玩的游戲
- Lie down. - I'll wait till you come up with a better game.
看到了嗎  乖狗狗
You see? Good girl.
別動  等著
Stay. Wait.
等等  不  洛奇  站住  洛奇
Wait. No, Rocky. Stop! Rocky!
握爪  握爪  來吧  狗狗
Paw. Paw. Come on, girl.
來吧  狗狗
Let's go, girl.
-什么是握爪  -握爪  來吧  握爪
- What is a paw? - Paw. Come on. Paw. Come on.
-來吧  -也許是這樣
- Let's go. - Maybe this is a paw?
乖狗狗  乖  乖狗狗
Good girl. Good, good girl!
我會握爪了  我會握爪了
I can do paw! I-I-I can do paw!
我同意  你順利從小狗學校畢業了
It's a deal. You have graduated puppy school right now.
-洛奇  回來  -真棒  乖狗狗
- Rocky, come back! - Good, good girl.
-洛奇  洛奇  -乖狗狗
- Rocky! Rocky! - Good girl.
我在學校的時候  你可以待在這里
You can stay here while I'm at school.
不許叫  好嗎
No barking, okay?
不是很明白現在是什么情況
Don't really understand what's happening.
等不及把這個給CJ看了
Can't wait to show this to CJ.
這是吃的嗎
Is that supposed to be food?
如果我不是真空上陣...
Maybe if I wasn't going commando...
什么聞起來這么香
Where'd that great smell come from?
我好喜歡
I love it.
CJ
CJ?
克拉里蒂  你聽到了嗎
Clarity, did you hear that?
我覺得是地下室傳來的  我去看看
I think it came from the basement. I'll check.
我在這兒  CJ
I, uh... I'm here, CJ!
你還記得
You-you remembered!
莫莉  噓
Molly, shh.
又是"噓"  "噓"是什么意思
Again with the "shh." What does "shh" mean?
媽媽  什么都沒有  我覺得是隔壁傳來的
Nothing here, Mom. I think it was next door.
揉肚肚  好不好
Belly rub, please.
我得告訴她你的事  莫莉
Gonna have to tell her about you, Molly.
媽媽  有件事我想向你交代
Mom, there's something I want to tell you.
如果你晚餐想訂披薩的話
So if you, uh, order a pizza for dinner,
不要全吃光  好嗎
do not eat the whole thing, okay?
生活對胖子很不友好
Life is harder when you're chubby.
更何況你說自己想當歌手
Plus, you claim you want to be a singer.
歌手必須漂亮
Got to look good.
感覺CJ像是被擊中了
It felt like CJ got hit,
但我沒看到是什么擊中了她
but I didn't see what hit her.
你想向我交代什么
What'd you want to tell me?
只是想知道你幾點能回家
Just wanted to know what time you'll be home.
不會太晚
Not too late.
媽媽
Mommy!
媽媽  我害怕
Mommy, I'm scared!
等等我  CJ
Wait for me, CJ!
CJ害怕了
CJ was afraid.
我也害怕了
I was afraid.
如果我保護她  也許她也會保護我
Maybe if I protect her, she'll protect me.
我以前很討厭媽媽很晚都不回家
I used to hate it when my mom stayed out late.
現在我有了你
And now I have you.
我再也不用害怕了
I don't have to be scared anymore.
我知道你會保護我
I know you'll protect me.
快讓那個聲音停下
Make that noise stop.
我真的真的很害怕
I'm really, really scared.
咚咚咚
Knock, knock.
早上好  親愛的
Hey, morning, sweetie.
早上好
Good morning.
我覺得給你做點早餐
So I thought it might be nice
應該很不錯
if I cooked you some breakfast.
什么  你會做早餐嗎
What? Do you even know how to do that?
傻孩子  我當然會
You silly. Of course I do.
我要出去  我憋不住了
I need to get outside. I need to go.
那...那是什么
Wh-What... what is that?
這是...這是...
This is, um... this is...
你一定就是克拉里蒂  我是保羅
You must be Clarity. I'm Paul.
這個小伙子是誰啊
And who's that little fella?
是小姑娘
Little gal.
-她叫莫莉  -我們要起床了嗎
- Her name's Molly. - Are we getting up?
說真的  我憋不住了
I seriously need to go.
太可愛了吧
What a sweetie.
-我喜歡狗  -是嗎
- I love dogs. - Oh, yeah?
我和媽媽也喜歡
Me and my mom do, too.
我得出去遛莫莉了
I have to take Molly out for a walk,
不過我們會回來吃早餐的
but we'll be back for breakfast.
好的
Okay.
-我先去準備雞尾酒  -好極了
- I'll go start those mimosas. - Great.
我們惹上麻煩了  莫莉  是的  大麻煩
We're in trouble, Molly. Yes, we are.
你背著我養了一條狗
You went behind my back and you got a dog?
你不許養狗
You're not allowed to have a dog.
聽明白了嗎
You understand me?
格洛麗亞聽起來很生氣
Gloria sounded angry.
氣味也很濃重
Smelled pretty strong, too.
寶貝  要再來一杯雞尾酒嗎
Hey, babe, you want another mimosa?
好啊  太好了
Oh, yeah, that'd be lovely.
我要留下她
I'm keeping her.
如果她會玩耍  也許就會開心一點
Maybe if she plays, she will feel happy.
我要留下莫莉
I'm keeping Molly.
我是你媽媽  我說了算
I am your mother, and I am the boss.
媽媽不應該讓十一歲的女兒夜里一人在家
And you're not supposed to leave your 11-year-old alone at night,
幾乎每晚都是
almost every night,
還是在嚇人的雷雨夜
during terrifying thunderstorms.
我的老師肯定很有興趣
I'm sure my teacher would be very interested
了解這樣的媽媽
in a mother who did that.
你是在威脅我嗎
Are you threatening me?
我會害怕
I get scared.
莫莉會保護我
Molly protects me.
你不能逼我送走她
You can't make me get rid of her.
懂了嗎
See?
她是我最好的朋友
She's my best friend.
我愿意為她做任何事
And I'll do everything for her.
你甚至都沒發現她在家
You didn't even know she was here.
這狗需要洗澡
That dog needs a bath.
你可以留下來了  你可以和我在一起了
You're staying with me. You get to stay with me.
好孩子  CJ  你是個好孩子
Good girl, CJ. You're a good girl.
沒錯  你的確需要洗澡
Yep, you do need a bath.
的確需要
Yep. You do.
看  莫莉  我的吊墜手鏈
Look, Molly, my charm bracelet.
上面有全世界我最愛的兩樣東西
It has my two favorite things in the whole world:
你和我的吉他
you and my guitar.
謝謝你給我看  雖然我不知道那是什么
Thank you for showing me whatever that is.
我要接著睡覺了
I will be going back to sleep now.
? 我都會 ?
♪ I'll be here ♪
? 陪著你 ?
♪ With you ♪
? 親近或遙遠 ?
♪ Near or far ♪
? 結束或開始 ?
♪ The end or the start... ♪
特倫特一如既往  總是很準時
Good old Trent, always on time.
洛奇一如既往  總是很準時
Good old Rocky, always on time.
首先  我來拉這根棍子
First, I'm gonna pull the stick,
然后你拉  然后我再拉
then you pull the stick, then I'll pull the stick.
看看我們的小狗
Look at our babies.
是啊  都長大了
Yep. All grown-up.
我們是不是該開始為上大學存錢了
Should we start saving for college?
莫莉和我并不是上大學的料  特倫特
Molly and I aren't exactly on the college track, Trent.
實際上我正在考慮退學
I'm actually thinking about dropping out of school.
要是我跟父母說要從高中退學
If I told my parents I was dropping out of high school,
他們會直接自燃
they would spontaneously combust.
好吧  我要盡快離開這里
Yeah, well, as soon as I can, I'm getting out of here.
我打算搬去紐約
I'm gonna move to New York City.
你打算怎么實現
And how are you gonna do that?
我爸死后有一筆保險理賠金
There was this insurance settlement when my dad died.
我滿十八了  終于能領這筆錢了
I finally get the money when I'm 18, so...
我準備用這筆錢搬去紐約
I'm gonna use it to move to New York,
錄樣帶  開始我的音樂人生涯
make a demo and get my career started as a musician.
你沒怎么提起過你爸爸
You hardly ever talk about your dad.
CJ需要我時  我就能感覺到
I-I can tell when CJ needs me.
等一下  洛奇  我去去就回
Hold on, Rocky. I'll be right back.
莫莉
Hey, Molly.
想坐下嗎  來吧
Want to sit? Come on.
那個...
Yeah, well...
我爸在我還沒出生時就去世了  所以...
died right before I was born, so...
我根本不了解他
I don't really know anything about him.
除了格洛麗亞說我小時候
Well, except Gloria said his parents tried to steal
他父母想偷走這筆錢
that money from me when I was a baby.
我也不知道
So... I don't know.
或許她半數時間都是醉醺醺的  但是...
Maybe she's drunk half the time, but...
她也算對我做了一件好事
she did do one good thing for me.
有時候CJ抱我抱得太緊
Sometimes CJ squeezed me so tight,
我都快喘不上氣了
I could barely breathe.
不過我喜歡
I loved it.
你想買東西嗎
Are you gonna buy something?
如果是的話  我就得再進去一趟
'Cause if you are, I got to go back in.
是的吧
Guess I was.
不過我不急
I'm not, like, in a hurry or anything, though.
我來猜猜
Let me guess.
一袋椒鹽卷餅和一瓶雪碧
A bag of pretzels and a Sprite.
是的  我可能特別好猜吧
Okay, I guess I'm pretty predictable.
我叫沙恩
Shane.
我叫CJ
CJ.
這是莫莉
That's Molly.
我對這個人有種不好的預感
I'm getting a bad feeling about this person.
它在做什么
What's it doing?
準備在我身上尿尿嗎
Getting ready to pee on me?
別激動  莫莉
Cool it, Molly.
抱歉
Sorry.
-你喜歡機車嗎  -算是吧
- So, you like motorcycles? - Kind of.
-是嗎  -別激動  莫莉
- Yeah? - Cool it, Molly.
你應該把球扔出去
You're supposed to throw the ball.
撿起球  再丟出去
You pick it up and throw it.
然后我把球撿回給你  你再扔出去
And then I get it and you throw it again.
不了  謝謝  狗狗
No, thanks, doggy.
他不明白
He doesn't understand.
他不怎么機靈
He's not too smart.
你想要這個嗎  莫莉
You want this, Molly?
你想玩撿球嗎
You want to go get it?
去撿吧
Go get it.
洛奇  特倫特
Rocky! Trent!
快速聞聞洛奇的屁屁
A quick sniff of Rocky's butt
我就知道洛奇一切安好
told me everything was going great for Rocky.
來吧  我們走
Come on, let's go.
特倫特
Hey, Trent.
-謝謝  -沒事
- Thanks. - Yeah.
這是沙恩
This is Shane.
他們都想加入CJ的家庭
Both of them want to be in CJ's pack.
你怎么了  怎么沒回我電話
What's up? Uh, you didn't return my call.
對了  抱歉  我有點忙
Oh, right. Sorry. I've... been kind of busy.
這是誰  你老媽嗎
Who is this, your mother?
雖然表面上他們沒有互相咆哮
They weren't growling at each other on the outside,
但我還是聽得見
but they were still growling.
你看看
Check it out.
下周有場選秀
Talent show, next week.
你有機會
This is a chance for you
真正在聽眾面前表演了
to actually perform in front of an audience.
我想你一定會很出色的
I bet you'd be great.
得了吧  你多少年沒聽過我唱歌了
Come on. You haven't heard me sing in years.
我知道  但你總有一天要在人們面前演出
I know, but you have to perform in front of people someday.
再說了  勝者有五百塊獎金
Plus, the winner gets $500.
去參加吧  CJ  你可以在
Yeah, do it, CJ. I mean, you can sing a song
魔術表演和啞劇之間唱首歌
between the magician and the mime.
確實有點遜  特倫特
Does look kind of lame, Trent.
不過還是謝謝你
Thanks, though.
咱們走吧
Let's hit it.
我們回頭見吧
Maybe I'll see you later?
那洛奇呢
Wh-What about Rocky?
我們本來想一起打滾呢
We were gonna roll in some stuff together.
莫莉  走了
Molly, come on.
? 那是個塵土飛揚的遙遠夜晚 ?
♪ It was a dusty old night ♪
One Way Ticket - The Darkness
? 而我是第一個承認的人 ?
♪ And I'm the first to admit it ♪
想找好吃的
You want something that tastes good,
應該試試這些襪子
you should try these socks.
? 我肯定惹人不快了 ?
♪ I'm sure I upset someone ♪
? 但我選擇性失憶 ?
♪ But my memory has chosen to omit it... ♪
我們應該順路去我哥們家
We should stop by my buddy's place.
他請了幾個人去聚聚
He's having a couple people over.
我該回家了
Well, I... I should probably get home.
明天還要上學
I've got school tomorrow.
別這樣  CJ  別掃興
Come on, CJ. Don't kill the fun.
好吧
Okay.
? 告訴我我做錯了 ?
♪ Let me know that I've done wrong ♪
Dirty Little Secret - The All-American Rejects
? 其實我一直都知道 ?
♪ When I've known this all along... ♪
我不想待在這
I did not want to be here.
CJ也一樣
Neither did CJ.
你不是說只會來
I thought you said only a couple of people
幾個人嗎
were gonna be here.
我說過嗎
Did I say that?
沙恩  我真的不喜歡這種活動
Shane, I'm really not into this.
-你能送我回家嗎  -等一會兒
- Can you take me home? - In a sec.
放輕松  喝點啤酒
Relax. Have some beer.
? 我會把你當作我不可告人的小秘密 ?
♪ I'll keep you my dirty little secret ♪
? 不可告人的小秘密 ?
♪ Dirty little secret ♪
? 別告訴任何人 ?
♪ Don't tell anyone ♪
? 否則你就會成為又一個遺憾 ?
♪ Or you'll be just another regret... ♪
快點  快點
Come on, come on!
-把酒放下  -走  走  走
- Put the drink down. - Go, go, go!
這里不是個好地方
This is not a good place.
我不喜歡這里  我們該走了
I do not like it here. We need to leave.
-我們走  -快走
- Let's go. - Let's move it!
其他人都走了
Other people are leaving.
我們也應該走
I think we should go, too.
等等  我的狗怎么辦
Wait. What's gonna happen to my dog?
等等  你不能讓我把狗丟下
Wait, you can't make me leave my do...
-上車  -你不能讓我把狗丟下
- Come. - You can't make me leave my dog.
莫莉
Molly!
CJ  你為什么要上那輛車
CJ, wh-why are you getting in that car?
你走了  我就不能保護你了
If you leave, I can't protect you.
CJ
CJ!
我不想待在這
I didn't want to be here.
我  我想跟CJ在一起
I-I... I wanted to be with CJ.
她在哪
Where was she?
-特倫特  -小姑娘
- Trent! - Hey, girl.
我得找到CJ
I need to find CJ.
我聞不到她
I don't smell her.
繼續開  聞到她我會叫的
Keep going. I'll bark if I smell her.
她在那兒
Th-there she is!
停車  我說了停車
S-Stop! I said stop!
莫莉
Molly.
CJ  我回來了
CJ, I'm back!
我找到你了
I found you.
謝謝你
Thank you.
特倫特把那個家伙趕走了
Trent got that other guy out of the pack.
我猜特倫特最終還是咬了他
I'm guessing he finally bit him.
我真是個傻瓜
I was such an idiot.
誰都有犯傻的時候
It happens.
你就從來沒做過錯誤的決定
You never make bad choices.
我太害怕我父母了
I'm too afraid of my parents.
至少你不用
At least you don't have to do
做一百小時的社區服務
a hundred hours of community service.
等等  你要像那些人一樣
Wait, so you're gonna be one of those people
到高速邊撿垃圾嗎
picking up trash on the side of the highway?
不是  我被分配到了一個
No, actually, I got assigned to this program
訓練狗聞出癌癥的項目
that trains dogs to sniff cancer.
-癌癥  -是的
- Cancer? - Yeah.
聽起來很不靠譜  但是...
Sounds pretty wacky, but...
至少我可以帶著莫莉一起
at least I get to take Molly with me.
德斯普蘭斯機構
先進醫療培訓及技術
這是個非常激動人心的試點項目
So, we're a pilot program, which is very exciting
因為我們取得了不少驚人的成果
because we've been getting amazing results.
等等  你是說
Wait, so you're telling me
這些狗能比醫生更早發現癌癥患者
these dogs know people have cancer before doctors do?
人類是眼觀世界  狗則是用鼻子聞
We see the world. Dogs smell it.
他們的嗅覺比人類要靈敏十萬倍
Their sense of smell is 100,000 times as acute as ours.
所以我們嘗試訓練狗  讓他們能夠
So, we're working on trying to get the dogs to recognize
辨別癌癥樣本和良性樣本
the difference between cancer samples and benign samples.
如果能成功訓練狗的嗅覺
If we successfully scent-train a dog,
就能改變一些人的生死
it can make the difference between life and death.
等等  我可以為狗進行嗅覺訓練嗎
Wait, so I get to scent-train a dog?
太酷了
That's so cool.
我喜歡你的熱情  但首先...
I love the enthusiasm, but first...
但愿CJ的使命不是這個
I hope this isn't CJ's purpose.
我們每天都去
We went every day.
CJ很開心  這也讓我很開心
CJ was happy, and that made me happy.
為什么他有吃的
Why is he getting treats?
我也想要吃的
I want treats, too.
-乖狗狗  波迪  -好吧
- Good dog, Bode. - Okay.
如果波迪再得到吃的
If Bode gets one more treat
我還是什么都沒有的話
and I get nothing,
我就要發飆了
I'm gonna go nuts.
好孩子  好孩子  波迪
Good boy. Good boy, Bode.
這個氣味
That smell.
波迪就是因為這個得到吃的的嗎
Is that why Bode gets treats?
如果我也...
Maybe if I...
-你看到了嗎  -嗯
- Did you see that? - Yeah.
好孩子
Good girl.
就是這樣
That's it.
如果你聞到了這個氣味  就會得吃的
If you smell the smell, you get a treat.
CJ  你介意我也開始訓練莫莉嗎
CJ, do you mind if I start training Molly, too?
好孩子  莫莉
Good girl, Molly.
? 權力屬于人民 ?
♪ People have the power ♪
People Have the Power - Patti Smith
? 權力屬于人民 ?
People have the power ♪
♪ People have the power... ♪
安靜
Quiet!
我認得這個氣味
I know that smell.
你好  格洛麗亞
Hi, Gloria.
很高興見到你
It's good to see you.
伊森和漢娜  終于出現了
Ethan and Hannah! Finally!
你好啊
Why, hello.
瞧瞧這是誰  你好
Who is this? Hello.
-伊森  是我  貝利  -你是誰
- Ethan! It's me, Bailey! - Hey. Who are you?
我現在是女孩了
I'm a girl now.
-怎么沒打招呼就來了  -格洛麗亞
- This is a surprise. - Gloria.
我們給你發了信息說我們會來這附近
We sent a note saying we're going to be in the area
希望你不介意我們順道拜訪
and we hoped it'd be okay to stop by.
有嗎  好吧
Did you? Okay.
肯定是沒看到
Must have missed that.
看  伊森  看
Look, Ethan, look!
我們在清理谷倉  找到了
We were cleaning out the barn, and we found a...
很多亨利的東西
a-a lot of Henry's things.
-我們想著...  -對
- We thought that... - Yes.
我們覺得你和CJ可能會想看看
We thought that you and CJ might like to see it.
有人看見我在干什么了嗎
Is anyone seeing what I'm doing here?
不管是什么  你們都可以郵寄過來
Yeah, you could have sent whatever that is.
我們想見你
Well, we wanted to see you.
我們想見CJ
We want to see CJ.
但我們不想見你們  所以...
Well, we don't want to see you, which is why...
伊森  是我  貝利
Ethan, it's me, Bailey!
你認不出我了嗎
Can't you tell it's me?
是你嗎  狗老大
Is that you, Boss Dog?
是我  是我  是我
It's me, it's me, it's me!
別叫了
Quiet!
格洛麗亞  我們只想見CJ
Gloria, we just want to see CJ.
你們憑什么覺得自己可以說來就來
What makes you think you can just show up like this?
我已經不是小孩子了
Okay, I-I-I'm not a little kid anymore,
不會再任你們擺布
so you can't... you can't push me around.
我們只想見我們的孫女
We want to see our granddaughter,
看看她過得怎么樣
just to see how she's doing.
我去告訴CJ你們來了
I'll go tell CJ you're here.
她不想見你們
Well, she doesn't want to see you.
-她在家嗎  -不關你們的事
- Is she home? - That is none of your business!
說了你都不信
You're not gonna believe it.
伊森和漢娜來了
Ethan and Hannah are here,
他們的氣味比以前更好聞了
and they smell better than ever.
-來  快來  -你在干什么
- Come! Come now! - Hey. What you doing?
走吧  跟我走
Let's go. Follow me.
離開你們  我們過得很好
We have a whole life without you.
-我很不喜歡這種伏擊  -"伏擊"
- I really don't appreciate this ambush. - "Ambush"?
格洛麗亞  我們是一家人
Gloria, we're family.
格洛麗亞
Gloria.
我們能從頭再來嗎  拜托
Can't we just start again? Please.
-讓我們重新開始  -格洛...
- Let's just start over. - Glo...
格洛麗亞  格洛麗亞  拜托
Gloria, Gloria, please.
你不記得伊森和漢娜了
Y-You forgot Ethan and Hannah.
別這么看我
Don't look at me like that.
這么多年過去了
All these years later,
他們還想把她從我身邊奪走
they still want to take her from me.
格洛麗亞
Gloria!
讓他們進來  是伊森和漢娜
L-Let them in. It's Ethan and Hannah.
我把它放在這兒
I'll just leave it here.
我知道是你  狗老大
I know that's you, Boss Dog.
我喜歡聽他叫我"狗老大"
I love it when he calls me "Boss Dog."
繼續照顧CJ
You just keep looking after CJ.
好
Okay.
不  別走
No, don't leave!
CJ在這兒
CJ's here.
來  莫莉  來
Come on, Molly. Come on.
好了
Okay.
干得好  莫莉
Good job, Molly.
安迪說你的嗅覺訓練進行得很順利
Andi says you've really taken to scent training.
給點吃的  拜托
Food, please.
離我們遠點
Leave us alone.
你來這里干什么
What are you doing here?
你不接我電話
You don't answer my calls.
因為我不想跟你說話  沙恩
Yeah, because I don't want to talk to you, Shane.
別這樣  CJ
Come on, CJ.
你不會還在因為派對的事生我的氣吧
You're not still mad about the party?
別不搭理我
Don't walk away from me.
放手  沙恩
Get off. Shane!
你干什么
What are you doing?
-我以為你沒這么慫呢  -沙恩
- I thought you were cooler than this. - Shane!
它咬我
It bit me!
滾開  CJ不喜歡你
Go away. CJ doesn't like you.
我要宰了那條蠢狗
I'm gonna kill that stupid dog!
我也不喜歡你
I don't like you, either.
理查德  如果是你
Richard, if that's you,
正好來把你的垃圾拿走
why don't you come get your junk?
是你啊
It's you.
理查德走了
Richard left.
沙恩剛剛襲擊了我
Shane just attacked me.
格洛麗亞的氣味比以往更濃重
Gloria smelled stronger than usual.
看來今天我們跟男人處得都不順利
Well... looks like today's not a good day for us and men.
是啊
Right.
你喝醉了
You're drunk.
對啊
Yeah.
成年人可以喝醉
Adults are allowed to get drunk
尤其是在被借到錢后
when they get dumped by their boyfriend
就再也不出現的男友甩了以后
who borrowed money they will never see again.
我說有人襲擊了我  媽媽
I just told you that some guy attacked me, Mom.
真的很可怕  你一點都不關心嗎
It was really scary. Do you even care?
你做了什么  你勾引他了嗎
Well, what did you do? Did you... did you lead him on?
你激怒他了嗎
Did you provoke him or something?
真不敢相信你居然這么說
I cannot believe you just said that.
你真的是世界上最惡劣的媽媽
You are literally the worst mother in the world.
不  最惡劣的是我媽媽
No, that was my mother.
我要走了
I'm leaving.
我不想再待在這里
I don't want to be here anymore.
我要帶上我的錢  然后搬出去
I'm taking my money, and I'm moving out.
-什么錢  -我爸爸的理賠金
- What money? - The money from Dad's settlement.
克拉里蒂  那筆錢已經沒了
Clarity, that money's gone.
什么
What?
你以為我們的房子是怎么來的
How do you think we have a house?
還有車
And a car?
但那筆錢是留給我的
But... but that money was for me.
你已經在用了  CJ
Well, it's been for you, CJ!
我孤身一人
I am alone.
-你怎么能指望我獨自承擔這一切  -等等
- How do you expect me to do... to do this on my own? - W-Wait.
所以那些...
So, all of the...
那些旅行  媽媽
all of the travel, Mom,
那些裝滿衣櫥的名牌衣服
the-the closet full of designer clothes,
一箱箱的葡萄酒...
the cases of wine...
花的都是我的財產
that... that's all been my inheritance?
我也值得擁有好東西
I deserve nice things, too.
媽媽  那筆錢是爸爸
Mom, that money was the only thing
唯一留給我的東西
I ever got from my dad.
那是唯一讓我覺得
That was the only thing that made me feel like,
也許這個世界上還有人
somewhere in the world, there might actually be
關心我的東西
someone looking out for me.
看來是我太傻了  對吧
But I guess that was really stupid, wasn't it?
你不能把車開走
You cannot take the car.
為什么不能  我付的錢
Why not? I paid for it.
我從來不知道
I never knew there could be
還有傷心兜風這回事
such a thing as a sad car ride.
什么
What?
沙恩
Shane?
別來煩我
Leave me alone.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我只想坐在座位上
All I wanted to do was stay
但車一直把我甩來甩去
on my seat, but the car kept pushing me off.
抱歉  莫莉
Sorry, Molly.
天啊
Oh, God.
什么
What?
這輛車瘋了
The car's gone crazy.
莫莉
Molly?
車總算停了
The car finally stopped.
你沒事吧  CJ
Are you okay, CJ?
莫莉  莫莉
Molly? Molly?
我喜歡這聲音
I love that sound.
說明CJ在旁邊
It means CJ's nearby.
莫莉  莫莉
Molly. Molly?
莫莉
Molly?
但我知道我要離開她了
But now I know I'm leaving her.
-我也不想  -莫莉
- I don't want to. - Molly.
但我別無選擇
But I have no choice.
莫莉
Molly.
-不  莫莉  -我記得農場里的小CJ
- No, Molly. - I remembered baby CJ on the farm
記得我多么想保護她
and how much I wanted to protect her.
記得她多么需要我
How much she needed me.
她的旅程...
Her journey...
還沒結束
is not over.
快來
Come on.
CJ很難過
CJ was so sad.
她還需要我
She still needs me.
CJ  不管你在哪  我發誓...
CJ, wherever you are, I promise...
我都會找到你
I'll find you.
但首先  我得處理些事情
But first, I need to get a few things out of the way.
我得玩耍  我得摔跤
I need to play. I need to wrestle.
我得啃臉
I need to bite a few faces.
我得吠叫
I need to bark.
我得玩毛毯
I need to play with a blanket.
我得咬耳朵
I need to bite some ears.
很不幸  我還是得洗澡
And, unfortunately, I still have to take baths.
我知道我的旅程應該和CJ在一起  但是...
I knew my journey was with CJ, but...
我到處都找不到她的氣味
I couldn't find her scent anywhere.
喬的便利店
過來  大狗
Come on, Big Dog.
現在我和喬一起生活
Now I lived with Joe.
-準備好迎接新的一天了嗎  -他對我很好
- Ready for another day? - He was good to me.
他住在一棟用零食做成的房子里
He lived in a house made out of snacks.
給你的
Just for you.
好好享用
Okay, bon appétit.
這是我的最愛
These are my favorite.
-慢慢享用  -我忘了這個
- Enjoy it. - I forgot about these.
不  這才是我的最愛
No, these are definitely my favorite.
你不能吃冰淇淋
No ice cream for you.
牛肉干怎么樣
How about a Slim Jim?
就是它
That's the one.
冠軍出現了
We have a winner.
我的最愛
My favorite.
后來有一天
Then, one day,
我聽到了讓我想起...
I heard something that reminded me of...
那個聲音
That sound.
早上好
Morning.
你好
Hi.
會是她嗎
Could it be?
再讓我聞一聞  確認一下
Maybe one more sniff, just to be sure.
今天過得怎么樣
How's your day going?
挺好的  謝謝
Pretty good, thanks.
一共四塊五
That'll be $4.50.
真不敢相信
I don't believe it.
是我的CJ  我找到你了
It's my CJ. I found you!
大狗
Big Dog.
他從來不為任何事起身
He never gets up for anything.
"大狗"  你怎么想到這個名字的
"Big Dog"? How'd you ever come up with that name?
靈光一現
Just sort of came to me.
你好  大狗
Hey there, Big Dog. Hey.
-現在我可以跟你走了  -你好嗎
- Now I can go with you. - How you doing?
我們去哪兒
Where are we going?
他肯定聞到你身上的狗味了
Must smell a dog on you.
我沒有養狗
I don't have a dog.
以前養過
Used to, though.
她叫莫莉  她是最棒的
Her name was Molly. She was the best.
她知道是我  我們終于重逢了
She knows it's me. We're finally back together.
握爪
Paw.
太可愛了
That is so sweet.
我教過我的狗握爪
I, um... I trained my dog to shake.
他從來沒做過
He's never done that before.
真的嗎
Really?
很高興認識你  大狗
Well, it's very nice to meet you, Big Dog.
我還要一張彩票刮刮卡
Can I also get a lottery scratch card?
你要去哪兒
So, where you headed?
紐約
New York City.
我希望喬告訴她我有多愛牛肉干
I hope Joe tells her about how much I love meat sticks.
搬去紐約工作還是...
You got a job or something?
我是一名唱作人
Well, I'm a singer-songwriter.
想成為一名唱作人  所以...
Trying to be a singer-songwriter, so...
不會吧  五十塊
Oh, no way. 50 bucks.
恭喜你
Congratulations.
這輩子從來沒中過獎
Never won anything before in my life.
你肯定是條幸運狗
You must be a lucky dog.
我還希望喬告訴她
And I hope Joe tells her about
那種嘎吱嘎吱的咸東西  太好吃了
the crunchy, salty things, too. Oh, they're so good.
謝謝
Thank you.
好了  再見
Okay. See ya.
-一路平安  -真希望我能感謝喬
- Travel safe. - I wished I could thank Joe for taking
一直以來把我照顧得這么好
such good care of me all this time.
我希望他知道我有多感激
I hoped he knew how grateful I was.
不  不  你得待在這里  大狗
Oh, no, no. You have to stay here, Big Dog.
CJ  不  我應該跟你走才對
CJ, no. I'm supposed to come with you.
CJ  等等  你在干什么
CJ, wait. What are you doing?
不  不  你不能丟下我
No! No, you can't leave me.
我和伊森說過我會保護你的
I told Ethan I would protect you.
大狗
Big Dog.
CJ  回來
CJ, come back.
我得幫助你
I need to help you.
大狗
Big Dog!
求你了  帶我走吧
Please, take me with you.
不  不  我不能失去你
No! No! I can't lose you.
我不會放棄的  我絕不會放棄
I will never stop. I will never stop.
慢一點
Slow... slow down.
對不起  我跑不了更快了
I'm sorry, I... I just can't run any faster.
來吧  大狗
Come on, Big Dog.
大狗
Big Dog.
來吧  來吧
Come on. Come on.
我絕不會放棄
I will never stop.
我絕不會放棄尋找你
I will never stop looking for you.
日復一日  但不見CJ
Day after day passed, but no CJ.
我不明白她為什么丟下我
I don't know why she left me behind.
我等了好久
I waited so long.
我越來越老
I got older and older.
當時候到了  我能感覺到
And when it was time, I knew.
我想我這輩子不會和CJ在一起了
I guess I wasn't gonna be with CJ in this life.
我這輩子和喬過得很幸福
I had a good life with Joe.
但是CJ沒有我的陪伴獨自生活  讓我很難過
But it was really hard knowing CJ was out there without me.
我知道我們的旅程還沒有結束
I knew our journey wasn't over.
這次回來我很嬌小
I came back small,
但是這不能阻止我
but I was not gonna let that stop me.
我已經出生過很多次  足以明白
I've been born enough times now to know
肚子餓了  就得奮斗
that when you're hungry, you have got to fight for it.
超級領養大派對
麥克斯
品種  三色約克夏?
年齡  八個月
體重  六磅
可供領養時間  今天
今天就帶我回家吧
顯然我的成長階段已經結束了
So, apparently, my growing phase was over.
我會保持嬌小的身材
I was gonna remain small.
跟貓一樣大小
Cat-sized.
如果我要找到CJ
If I was gonna find CJ,
就需要一個新策略
I was gonna need a new strategy.
瞧瞧你  你真可愛
Look at you. You are so cute.
我已經屬于別人了
I already belong to somebody.
我們想找年齡大一些的狗
We're really looking for an older dog.
我有適合你們的完美選擇
I have the perfect dog for you.
對不住  別往心里去
Sorry about that. Nothing personal.
真惹人喜歡
How sweet.
這個小可愛正好能裝進我的包里
This little cutie would fit in my purse.
不行
Nope.
看別的去
Keep moving.
不錯啊  老伙計
Good going, old guy.
她會很難搞的
She's gonna be tricky.
等等  等等
Wait. Wait.
我記得這個聲音
I know that sound.
會是她嗎
Could it be?
我覺得可能是
I think it might be.
如果是呢
What if it is?
很抱歉  麥克斯
I'm sorry, Max,
但是我不得不帶你回收容所了
but I'm gonna have to take you back to the shelter.
我必須搞清楚
I have to find out.
我也不想這么做  但是...
I don't want to have to do this, but...
-對不起  你是個好人  -麥克斯
- Sorry. You've been great. - Max!
-謝謝你提供食物和水  -麥克斯  麥克斯
- Thanks for all the food and water. - Max, Max!
這地方太大了
This place is huge.
快讓開  有狗經過
Out of my way. Dog coming through.
對不住
Sorry about that.
身材小巧確實也有優勢
Being small does have some advantages.
聞起來好香  只舔一下就好
Wow, that smells good. Maybe just one lick.
不  算了
No, forget that.
這次我不能再讓她離開了
I cannot let her get away this time.
我什么都看不見
I can't see a thing.
紐約雙層觀光巴士
我需要去更高的地方
I need to get to higher ground.
廣場公園面積9.7英畝
...Square Park is a 9.7-acre park...
太好了  她在那兒
Oh, yeah! There she is!
下午好
Afternoon.
我腿短但是跑得快
My legs are short but fast.
這次我不會再失去你了
I'm not gonna lose you this time.
CJ  我的CJ
CJ. My CJ.
-我找到你了  -你好
- I found you. - Oh, hello.
你在干什么
What you doing?
不不不  過來
Oh, no, no, no, no. Come here.
這東西怎么解開
How do you get this thing off?
我來了
Here I am.
來保護你
Here to protect you.
還是很美味
Still delicious.
你從哪來的
Where did you come from?
領養我
曼哈頓動物收容所
謝謝
Thank you.
我想這里發生了越獄
Think there was a jailbreak.
這是麥克斯嗎
Is that Max?
麥克斯
Max.
你真可愛  麥克斯
You are such a love dog, Max.
你是這世上唯一一個
You're the only person in the world
沒被他咬的人
he hasn't tried to bite.
就像是他選中了你
It's like he chose you.
我不行  我和我男友一起住
I can't. I-I live with my boyfriend,
他已經有一條狗了  我...
and he already has a dog. I...
我真的不能再帶一條回家了
I really can't bring home another one.
太遺憾了
That's too bad.
他明天就要被安樂死了
He's scheduled to be put down tomorrow.
等等  你是說真的嗎
Wait, are you serious?
我們盡力把狗送到
W-We do our best to foster out
無殺戮收容所  但是都住滿了
to no-kill shelters, but they're full.
我們也滿了
We're full.
麥克斯占的位置可以給另一條狗
Max is taking a place that could go to another dog.
-但你不能...  -救助就像一條河流
- But you can't... - Rescue's like a river.
必須要不停流動  不然就會倒退
It has to keep flowing, or it backs up.
杜克
Duke?
坐下
Sit.
好的
Okay.
坐下  麥克斯
Sit, Max.
對  你坐下  就那樣不要動
Yeah. You sit, and you stay that way.
明白了嗎
Get me?
這是麥克斯
This is Max.
你們倆會成為很好的朋友的
You two are gonna be very good friends.
就像她說的  現在我是老大了
Like she said, I'm the boss now.
? 人生有高潮也有低谷 ?
♪ There's a high and a low... ♪
CJ總是為我們制造聲音
CJ was always making sounds for us.
? 我保證我會 ?
♪ I promise I'll ♪
我喜歡這些聲音
I liked them.
? 一直... ?
♪ Always be... ♪
在嗎  CJ
Hello, CJ?
我回來了
I'm back.
杜克
Duke.
這個男人是誰  為什么
Who is this man, and why is he
-他進我們家了  CJ  -乖一點
- in our house, CJ? - Be nice.
我知道  我知道  我也想你
I know, I know. I missed you, too.
旅途順利嗎
How was your trip?
-你們要把我擠扁了  -順利  你好嗎
- You're crushing me. - It was good. How are you?
挺好的
Good. Yeah.
這就是你跟我說起的那條狗
So, that's the dog you told me about.
嗯
Yep.
保持你的距離
Keep your distance.
現在CJ由我保護
I'm protecting CJ now.
很有個性
Great personality.
他只是需要一點時間適應
He just needs a minute to warm up.
有個玩伴杜克很高興
And Duke loves having a playmate.
而且唱歌給兩條狗聽
And I guess playing your music for two dogs is
比一條狗聽要好  對吧
better than one dog, right?
對  它們是很好的聽眾
Right. They're a good audience.
可惜狗不會買專輯
Too bad dogs don't buy records.
等我準備好了  就會唱給別人聽  好嗎
Look, I'm gonna play for people when I'm ready. All right?
CJ每天要遛一大群狗
Every day, CJ walked a huge group of dogs.
他們知道我說了算
They knew I was in charge.
林戈玩得很開心
So Ringo had a great time.
-他尿了兩次  -很好
- He, um, peed twice. - Oh, great.
-謝謝  -謝謝
- Thank you. - Thank you.
-再見  -再見
- See ya. - Bye.
這個盒子聞起來像...
This box has smells like, uh...
麥克斯  你要去哪兒
Max, where are you going?
抱歉
Sorry.
-這邊  -麥克斯
- This way! - Max!
麥克斯  回來
Max, come back.
麥克斯
Max.
特倫特
Trent!
-CJ  -特倫特
- CJ? - Trent?
洛奇在哪
Where's Rocky?
,  -你怎么在這...我...
- What are you...? - What are you...? I...
這太奇怪了
This is so weird.
我的狗剛把我拽到這來了
My dog just dragged me here.
但我不知道...
But I don't know...
你住在這里嗎
Do you live here?
是的  我剛搬進來
Yeah, I just moved in.
這個小家伙是誰
Who's this little guy?
這是麥克斯  小心點
That's Max. Be careful.
他不是很友好
He's not very friendly.
特倫特  我好高興見到你
Trent, I'm so glad to see you.
洛奇在哪
Where's Rocky?
我覺得他挺友好的
He seems pretty friendly to me.
真不敢相信你在紐約
I can't believe you're in New York.
我從來沒覺得你喜歡大城市
I never saw you as a big-city guy.
我之前在倫敦住了一陣
Well, I was in London for a while.
然后這里有了新機遇
And when the opportunity came up here,
我心里想  "為什么不試試呢"
I thought to myself, "Why not give it a try?"
我的鼻子告訴我洛奇不在了
My nose told me Rocky was gone.
可憐的特倫特
Poor Trent.
人沒有狗是不可能幸福的
A person can't be happy without a dog.
這個地方很棒
Well, it's a pretty nice place.
你肯定過得不錯
You must be doing okay.
我想知道這里的吃的都放在哪里
I wonder what the snack situation is here.
抱歉
Sorry.
你了解我的  我一向循規蹈矩
You know me. I follow the rules.
我一直很佩服你完全不在乎那些規矩
I always admired how you didn't care about the rules.
是啊  格洛麗亞沒有教會我遵守規矩
Yeah, well, Gloria didn't exactly teach me to follow rules.
你媽怎么樣
How is your mom?
我不知道
I don't know.
我好幾年沒和她聯系了
I haven't spoken to her in years.
你的音樂生涯呢
How's the music career?
挺好的
Good. Yeah.
我是說挺不容易的
I mean, it's hard.
而且  我現在要遛這么多狗
Plus, I'm walking all these dogs now
才能付清賬單
just to pay the bills.
所以...
So it's...
真是松了口氣
That's a relief.
有那么一瞬間  我以為你變成了
For a second, I thought you'd become
那種失控的囤狗女士
one of those out-of-control dog ladies.
CJ很開心  這讓她笑了
CJ was happy, and it made her laugh.
她跟巴里在一起時從沒笑過
She never laughs with Barry.
好了  我該走了
All right, well, I should probably get going.
好
Yeah.
我女友下周末會來
My girlfriend is coming in next weekend.
也許我們可以跟你和你男友一起
Maybe we could do a double date
來個四人約會
with you and your boyfriend?
好的  我們很樂意
Yeah, sure, we'd love that.
好
Okay.
離開特倫特后  CJ似乎很傷心
CJ seemed sad after we left Trent.
我能看出來她想要特倫特加入我們的家庭
I could tell she wanted Trent in our pack.
我也想
So did I.
也就是說...
Which meant...
巴里必須走
Barry had to go.
CJ
CJ!
這是巴里的
Barry's.
CJ
CJ!
我已經憋了一整天了
I've been holding this in all day,
該釋放了
and it's go time.
CJ
CJ!
棒極了
Yes!
我只是說說  但是如果要咬他才能趕走他
Just saying, if I have to bite this guy to get rid of him,
我絕對會咬
I absolutely will.
領養一條狗真是個愚蠢的決定
Adopting a dog was such a stupid decision.
你為什么要這么說
Why are you saying that?
看看你  CJ
Look at you, CJ.
你的事業毫無前途
Your career is nowhere.
好吧  謝謝評價  巴里
Okay, thanks, Barry.
我不需要別人幫我變得更郁悶
I don't need any help feeling bad about myself.
是嗎  我只是覺得你沒有天賦
Yeah, well, I just don't think you have what it takes.
我不想住在這里了
I don't want to be here anymore.
你要去哪
Where are you gonna go?
你退租了自己的公寓  也沒有錢
You gave up your apartment. You have no money.
是啊  我會想辦法的
Yeah, well, I will figure something out.
-不許離開我  -別碰我
- Don't walk away from me. - Don't touch me.
我們  不喜歡  你
We... don't... like... you.
杜克
Duke?
謝謝
Thanks.
阿曼達下周二回來
Amanda comes back next Tuesday.
她說你可以暫住
She said it would be okay.
我們這里不允許養狗  所以把他藏好
We're not allowed dogs here, so keep him on the down-low.
好的  謝謝
Okay. Thanks.
我把巴里趕走了
So I got rid of Barry,
但是特倫特并沒有加入我們
but Trent didn't join our pack.
這說不通啊
It didn't make any sense.
紐約大學
第五大道35號
american dream - LCD Soundsystem
? 在有人陪伴下醒來 ?
♪ Wake up with somebody near you... ♪
我和CJ相依為命  而我們四處漂泊
It was just me and CJ, and we moved around a lot.
我們總是在散步
We went on a lot of walks.
每過幾天  我們就換一個新地方睡覺
Every couple of days, we were sleeping somewhere new.
但是我們從沒見過特倫特
But we never saw Trent,
盡管我們知道他在哪
even when we knew where he was.
? 看著胡子在臉上蔓延 ?
♪ Watched the beard crawl around on your face... ♪
我一直陪著CJ  但是
I stayed close to CJ, but...
她看起來還是很難過
she still seemed sad.
? 變革已經發生 ?
♪ Oh, the revolution was here ♪
? 這將給予你自由 ?
♪ That would set you free from those... ♪
你去攔出租車好嗎
Can you go get a cab?
-好  有幾輛過來了  -麥克斯  過來
- Yeah, there's a few coming. - Max, come on. Max.
-過來  -特倫特
- Come on. - Trent!
麥克斯
Max.
CJ  你怎么回事
CJ, what's wrong with you?
-你沒聞到特倫特嗎  -謝謝
- Don't you smell Trent? - Thank you.
一定要攔到出租車  我可不想遲到
Okay, make sure you get that cab over there. I don't want to be late.
-麥克斯  噓  -我明白
- Max, shh, shh. - I got it, I got it.
-拜托  噓  -我終于明白了
- Please, shh. - I finally get it.
-麥克斯  過來  -"噓"表示"叫大點聲"
- Max, come here. - "Shh" means "Bark louder."
-麥克斯  噓  -好的  沒問題  CJ
- Max, shh, shh. - Okay. Will do, CJ.
麥克斯
Max?
特倫特  我們在這兒  我來了
Trent, we're right here! Here I come.
張開你的雙臂  接住我
Open your arms and catch me.
麥克斯
Max.
我說了接住我
I said catch me.
你認識這條狗
You know this dog?
你怎么還不把那只貓放下來抱我
Why don't you put that fancy cat down and pick me up?
CJ
CJ.
-抱歉  -你好
- Sorry. - Hi.
這就是我跟你說過的老朋友
This is the old friend I was telling you about.
莉斯爾  這是CJ
Liesl, CJ.
-CJ  這是莉斯爾  -你好
- CJ, Liesl. - Hi.
你好  很高興認識你
Hi. Nice to meet you.
我給你留言了好幾次
So I left you a bunch of messages.
你都沒有回我
You didn't get back.
-一切都還好嗎  -是的
- Is everything okay? - Oh, yeah.
是的  抱歉  一切都很好
Yeah, sorry. Um, everything's great.
真的都很好
Really great, actually.
我  我本來打算
I, um... I-I was gonna, um...
我
I was...
CJ
C-CJ?
抱歉
Sorry.
這里聞起來可比我們昨天睡的地方好多了
This smells way better than the place we slept last night.
你家真漂亮
Place looks great.
嗯
Yeah.
你可以住在這邊的客房
You can stay right here in the guest bedroom
直到你找到住處
until you find your own place.
很抱歉  我也不想給你添麻煩的
I'm sorry. I don't mean to be such a pain.
你沒給我添麻煩
You're not being a pain.
我只是需要一點時間讓生活重新回到正軌
I just need a little time to get back on my feet.
特倫特
Trent?
我能跟你單獨說幾句嗎
Can I speak with you for a second?
好了
Okay.
我猜那條狗不會走路
I guess that dog doesn't know how to walk.
我好像給你惹麻煩了
Feel like maybe I'm getting you into trouble.
沒關系的
It's fine.
莉斯爾是個小醋壇子
Liesl can be a little jealous.
我們能坐一會兒嗎
Is it okay if we sit down?
我累死了
I'm exhausted.
當然可以
Yeah, sure.
你沒事吧
You okay?
沒事  只是...
Yeah. Yeah, just, uh...
也許我工作太拼了
think I'm working too much.
讓一讓
Excuse me.
特倫特告訴我你是職業遛狗人
So, Trent tells me that you're a professional dog walker.
你是怎么了
What happened to you?
是的
Yeah.
不過只是副業
Just on the side.
音樂才是我真正在乎的事業
Music is what I really care about.
這么說你有樂隊
So you have a band?
沒有樂隊
Nope. No band.
只有我和我的吉他
Just me and my guitar.
那你在哪里演出
Where do you play?
我還沒有正式演出過
I haven't exactly booked a gig yet.
只是一直在寫自己的歌
Kind of just been working on my songs.
面對聽眾前  我想先準備好全套曲目
I wanted to have a whole set before I started playing in public.
所以  音樂才是副業
So, I mean, music is on the side,
遛狗才是你真正的職業  對嗎
and dog walking is your real job, then, right?
莉斯爾沒有撒尿標記
Liesl didn't pee on anything,
但她絕對是在宣誓主權
but she was definitely marking her territory.
等不及開飯了
Ready for food here.
快點  把碗放下
Let's go. Put the bowl down.
好好好
Okay, okay.
坐下
Sit.
好孩子
Good boy.
太美味了  最美味的一餐
This is delicious. Best meal ever.
慢點  麥克斯
Slow down, Max.
我吃完了
I'm done.
特倫特
Trent!
難熬的一天
Tough day?
不算太糟
Not too bad.
我可能只是缺覺
Think I just need some sleep.
-肯定是  -你好啊  小家伙
- Yeah, I bet. - Oh, hey, little guy.
我剛剛吃了一生中最美味的一餐
I literally just had the best meal of my life.
特倫特回到我們的家庭了  真好
Good to have Trent back in the pack.
我能說幾句也許不太中聽的話嗎
Can I say something you may not want to hear?
說吧
Sure.
我覺得你怯場
I think you have stage fright.
等等  這氣味
Wait, that smell.
我
I...
行  好吧
Okay, fine.
也許我是有點怯場
Maybe I have a little stage fright.
但是...我不知道
But... well, I don't know.
也許我的歌還不夠好
Maybe my songs just aren't ready yet.
這個嘛
Well...
我還是莫莉的時候就聞過這種氣味
I remember that smell from when I was Molly.
如果你不演唱  怎么能知道
How will you know whether they're ready
你的歌夠不夠好
if you don't play them?
對嗎
Right?
這個小把戲真可愛
That's a cute little trick.
我聞到氣味了  我該得到吃的了
I smelled the smell. Now I get a treat.
看到了嗎
You see that?
特倫特  你這種疲憊感持續多久了
Trent, how long have you been wiped out like this?
"疲憊感"
"Wiped out"?
實際上...我從倫敦搬回來后就一直是這樣
Actually... since I moved back from London.
我可能還在倒時差
I guess I'm... I'm just jet-lagged.
是不是去找醫生看看比較好
You... do you think maybe you should see a doctor?
只是檢查一下
Just to make sure everything's okay?
你在轉移話題  逃避談論你的音樂生涯
You're changing the subject from your musical career.
我會好好考慮的  好嗎
I am gonna think about that, okay?
你去找個醫生看看好嗎
Will you just please go see a doctor?
-好吧  -打擾一下
- Okay. - Excuse me.
你還欠我吃的呢
You owe me a treat.
格洛麗亞
格洛麗亞  別再打了
Gloria, stop calling me.
? 有一個女孩...  ?
♪ There's a girl... ♪
請進
Come in.
莉斯爾來了
Liesl's here.
你能出來一下嗎
Could you come out?
我有事要告訴你們兩個
I want to tell you both something.
好的
Sure.
他們確定是癌癥嗎
And they're sure it's cancer?
確定
They're sure.
他們跟你談了哪些治療方案
What did they tell you about treatment options?
好消息是  確診及時
Well, the good news is, uh, they caught it early.
但是我得做化療
But I'll have to do chemo.
你一定要去醫院嗎
Do you have to go to the hospital?
我討厭醫院  我害怕醫院
I hate hospitals. They terrify me.
你知道的
You know that.
那就千萬別得癌癥
Then definitely don't get cancer.
你笑什么
Why are you laughing?
開個玩笑而已
It was... it was just a joke.
你覺得現在是開玩笑的時候嗎
Do you really think that this is the time to joke?
我要去透透氣
I... I need some air.
會沒事的
It'll be okay.
謝謝
Thanks.
她怎么說
And what did she say?
她說她可不想當護士
She said she's not up for being a nurse.
真冷血
That is pretty cold.
抱歉
Sorry.
也許這樣更好
Maybe it's for the better.
不然她大概也會用這件事來搏關注
She'd probably find some way of making it about herself anyway.
你知道你能戰勝癌癥的
You know you're gonna beat this.
對嗎
Right?
當然
Definitely.
應該吧
I-I think.
我還是不敢相信
I-I still can't believe this.
我哪兒也不會去
Well, I'm not going anywhere.
謝謝  CJ
Thanks, CJ.
一切都會好起來的
Everything's gonna be fine.
他們讓我想起了伊森和漢娜年輕的時候
They remind me of Ethan and Hannah when they were young.
他們想舔對方嗎
Do they want to lick each other?
我得去醫院了  麥克斯
I got to go to the hospital, Max.
等我回來  我們就好好出去散個步  好嗎
When I get back, we'll go on a long walk, okay?
特倫特走了  CJ也經常離家
Trent went away, and then CJ was gone a lot.
別動  麥克斯
Stay, Max.
如果你不想帶我散步  為什么要提起來呢
Why say "walk" if you don't mean "walk"?
特倫特回家了  他經常在睡覺
Trent came home, and he slept a lot.
睡的時間比我都長
He slept even more than me.
謝謝
Thank you.
我一直在咬這個癢癢的地方
And I'd been biting at this itch for a long time.
你真的很喜歡咬那個地方  是嗎
Boy, you're really chewing that spot, aren't you?
也許我該帶你去看獸醫
Maybe I should take you to the vet.
好了
Okay.
味道如何
So?
非常好
It's really good.
真的嗎
Really?
不  很難喝
No, it's horrible.
我來嘗嘗
Here, I'm gonna try it.
真的很難喝
It's really bad.
雖然特倫特一直待在家里
Trent wore clothes for outside
但他一直穿著外套
even though he always stayed inside.
-很健康  味道也很健康  -他看起來很滑稽
- It's healthy. Tastes healthy. - He looked ridiculous.
很抱歉  麥克斯
I'm sorry, Max.
等你的腿愈合了  我們就摘掉它  好嗎
As soon as your leg heals, we'll take it off, okay?
我也不知道  麥克斯
I don't know, Max.
每次我想起在聽眾面前演唱
Every time I think about playing in public,
我的心就會砰砰地跳
my heart just starts racing.
我也不知道  也許我沒有那種天賦
I don't know. Maybe I don't have what it takes.
真希望這張床是培根做的
I wish this bed was made out of bacon.
你不小心把你的鑰匙給別人了
You accidentally gave someone your key?
還有比這更美好的生活嗎
Does life get any better than this?
是醫生
It's the doctor.
你好  羅賓斯醫生
Hi, Dr. Robbins.
好的  那是什么意思
Okay, so what does that mean?
好的
Okay.
謝謝  我會的
Thank you. Will do.
她怎么說
What did she say?
她說我的檢查結果沒問題
Sh-Sh-She said my... my scans were clean.
我沒有癌癥了
I'm cancer-free.
-真的嗎  -是的
- Really? - Yeah.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我不知道我們為什么這么高興
I don't know why we're happy,
但我也高興起來了
but it makes me happy.
過來  過來
Come here. Come here.
對  對
Right, right.
特倫特又陪我們散步了
Trent came on our walks again.
有他回來真好
It was so great having him back.
格洛麗亞一直在給我發短信
Gloria keeps texting me.
她要來紐約了
She's coming to New York.
你要見她嗎
You're gonna go see her?
不知道
I don't know.
好多年沒見了
It's been years, you know?
再說  她讓我覺得很自卑
Plus, she makes me feel terrible about myself.
她對你的影響還是很大
She still has too much power over you.
如果你近看她
If you see her up close,
你會發現  她只是個普通人
you'll just realize she's just another person.
是啊  也許你說的對
Yeah, maybe you're right.
你幫我挺過了癌癥
You just got me through cancer.
你可以直面格洛麗亞
You can face Gloria.
現在輪到我支持你了
Now I can be here for you.
來吧  快舔臉
Come on, lick faces.
特倫特
Trent...
快舔  你們都想這么做
Do it. You both want to.
你真是個好朋友
You're a really good friend.
他們什么時候才會...
Are they ever going to...
我聞到了新鮮的便便
I smell fresh poop!
焦褐咖啡
這邊
Right this way.
我不明白
I didn't understand
-為什么CJ在發抖  -謝謝
- why CJ was trembling. - Thank you.
沒有風  天氣也不冷
It wasn't windy or cold.
請坐吧
Please, sit down.
抱歉  我得帶著他一起來
I'm sorry I had to bring him with me.
當然了  沒關系的
Oh, of course. That's okay.
你真漂亮
You're so beautiful.
-喝點水吧  -謝謝
- Some water. - Thank you.
你一直和特倫特住在一起嗎
So, you've... you've been living with Trent?
你們在交往嗎
Is that... Are you two... are you dating?
他一直都對你有意思
Well, he always had such a thing for you.
不  我們只是朋友
No, we're, um... we're just friends.
你的音樂怎么樣了
And what is going on with your music?
只是寫寫歌
Just writing songs and...
我在考慮錄樣帶
you know, thinking about maybe making a demo.
面對聽眾
It's gonna be...
你肯定會害怕吧
scary to get up in front of an audience.
嗯  我還在考慮自己到底是不是這塊料
Yeah. Kind of wondering if I'm cut out for it.
如果你不去試試  怎么會知道呢
Well, if you don't try, you'll never know.
你來這干什么呢  格洛麗亞
So, what are you doing here, Gloria?
先說一聲  我可沒錢
Just so you know, I don't have any money.
我不想從你這要錢
No, I don't want money from you.
格洛麗亞的感覺變了
I felt a different feeling from Gloria.
不是憤怒  而是難過
Not angry. Sad.
-麥克斯  她討厭狗  -天哪
- Max, she hates dogs. - Oh, God.
我能抱抱他嗎
Can I... can I hold him?
好的
Yeah.
想和我一起坐坐嗎
Want to come s-sit with me?
如果說誰最需要狗
If anybody ever needed a dog,
那肯定是格洛麗亞
it was Gloria.
她需要感受愛
She needed love.
有這么一條狗
It must be nice to have...
無條件地愛你  感覺肯定很好
something that loves you like this, without conditions.
因為你大概很需要無條件的愛
Because you probably really needed that.
是啊
Yeah, I did.
克拉里蒂  我...
So, Clarity, I...
我已經戒酒了
I have been sober for, um,
戒了九個月零十三天
nine months and 13 days.
而且
And...
我不是一個好媽媽
I was not a good mother.
我很抱歉  克拉里蒂
And I am s-so sorry, Clarity.
還有
And...
如果你愿意
if you'd let me, I'd...
我真的很想回到你的生活中
really like to be a part of your life.
我也很想相信你  格洛麗亞
I really want to trust you, Gloria.
我只是不確定自己能不能做到
I just don't know if I can.
下周就是你爸爸的生日了
So, it's your father's birthday next week.
我不知道你是否知道
I don't know if you knew that.
而且你馬上就要到
And you are about to turn the age
他去世時的年齡了
that he was when he died.
太難以置信了
Which is so crazy.
我這兒有一些他寫的信
I have some, uh, letters from him
是我懷孕時他寄給我的
that he wrote to me when I was pregnant...
懷著你的時候
with you.
你的爺爺奶奶把信給了我
and your grandparents gave them to me.
我覺得你應該收下
And I... I think you should have them.
他去世的時候  我很氣憤
I was so angry when he died.
也很害怕
And... scared.
我迷茫了
And I was just... lost.
但現在  我明白了
But, um, I realize now
你應該知道他是個什么樣的人  這很重要
it is so important that you know who he was.
因為他...
Because he was...
我不想看這些信  格洛麗亞
I don't want to read these, Gloria.
你想看的
Oh, yes, you do.
沒錯
Yeah.
在這件事上  你得相信我
Just trust me on that one thing.
還有
And, um...
我知道這也許需要時間
I know it-it may take time.
我真心希望有一天你可以原諒我
I do hope that someday you can forgive me.
原來格洛麗亞也挺會撓耳朵的
Turns out Gloria's a pretty good ear scratcher, too.
或許她還有希望
Maybe there is hope for her, after all.
這些紙聞起來像漢娜的兒子
The papers smelled like Hannah's boy.
讓我想起了伊森和漢娜  還有農場
They made me think of Ethan and Hannah and the farm.
格洛麗亞  我很想你
Gloria, I miss you.
我想我會被摩托羅拉聘用
I think I'm gonna get the Motorola job.
上周我看了一間公園旁的公寓
I saw an apartment next to a park
很適合帶孩子一起住
that would be perfect for the baby.
我知道我們都很害怕
I know we're both scared,
但我終于開始明白了
but I finally have some clarity.
我們那么年輕  都不知道自己在干些什么
We're so young, and we don't know what we're doing.
但我們擁有彼此
But we have each other,
我們會一起想明白該怎么辦
and we will figure it out together.
我們可以去密歇根州的農場  跟我媽和伊森
We can spend the summer with my mom and Ethan
一起度過這個夏天
at the farm in Michigan.
我知道我媽肯定可以幫我們很多忙
I know my mom will be super helpful to us.
要當奶奶了  她非常興奮
She is so excited to be a grandmother.
我等不及想見我們的女兒了
I cannot wait to meet our little girl.
怎樣才能養育一個堅強  無所畏懼的孩子
How do you raise a child to be strong and bold?
讓她相信自己
To believe in herself?
有你當她的媽媽  她肯定會有一個好的開始
She'll have a good start with you as her mom.
我為她  為我們抱有很多的期待
I have so many dreams for her and for us.
真不敢相信我會接受我媽的建議  但是...
Can't believe I'm taking my mother's advice, but...
如果不試  我永遠也不知道  對嗎  麥克斯
if I don't try it, I'll never know, will I, Max?
-對嗎  -有時候  你能做到的最好的事
- Will I? - Sometimes the best thing you can do
就是陪在她身邊
is just be there.
就算你的肋骨被壓著了
Even if your ribs get
讓你有點憋不住
a little bit crushed and it makes you want to go.
約翰尼·G餐館酒吧
? 一直以來 ?
♪ All the times ♪
? 我都在懷疑自己 ?
♪ I doubted myself ♪
? 還有那些 ?
♪ All these stories ♪
? 難以言說的故事 ?
♪ That I couldn't tell ♪
? 沒有勇氣 ?
♪ Wouldn't stand
? 站在人群之前 ?
♪ In front of a crowd ♪
? 亦或大聲道出我的想法 ?
♪ Or say my thoughts too loud ♪
? 但我感受到灼熱的火焰 ?
♪ But there's a fire I'm feeling ♪
? 在我心中熊熊燃燒 ?
♪ That burns me up ♪
? 生平第一次 ?
♪ For once in my life ♪
? 我準備好放手一躍 ?
♪ I'm ready to jump ♪
? 我在墜落  無所畏懼 ?
♪ I'm falling, fearless ♪
? 這是唯一的辦法 ?
♪ No other way to do this ♪
? 因為即使我在墜落 ?
♪ 'Cause even when I'm crashing down ♪
? 還有更高的境界 ?
♪ There is higher ground ♪
? 我在墜落  無所畏懼 ?
♪ I'm falling, fearless ♪
? 這是唯一的辦法 ?
♪ No other way to do this ♪
? 因為即使我在墜落 ?
♪ 'Cause even if I'm crashing down ♪
? 此時此刻  我樂在其中 ?
♪ I'm in this moment now ♪
? 我在墜落  無所畏懼 ?
♪ I'm falling, fearless. ♪
Take Your Time - Sam Hunt
? 我不想奪去你的自由 ?
♪ I don't want to steal your freedom... ♪
你太棒了
You're so great.
天吶
My God.
你做到了
You did it.
我太為你驕傲了
I'm so proud of you.
你不感到開心嗎
Don't you feel good?
我感到釋懷了
I, uh... I feel relieved.
那首關于你爺爺奶奶的農場的歌非常打動我
That song about your grandparents' farm really got to me.
你去過那里嗎
Have you even been there?
那時候我還是個嬰兒  不過...
Just when I was a baby, but...
我也不知道  看了我爸的信之后
I don't know. Reading my dad's letters,
我好像記起來了
I kind of felt like I remembered it.
我一直在找機會報答你和麥克斯
I've been trying to think of a way to repay you and Max.
今晚讓我有了一個瘋狂的想法
Tonight just gave me this crazy idea.
你愿意來一次公路旅行嗎
Would you be up for a road trip?
歡迎來到密歇根州
我喜歡坐車  但我為什么被拴住了
I love car rides, but why am I tied down?
我真的很想把頭伸出窗外
I really would like to put my head out the window.
他喜歡坐車
He loves car rides.
這些氣味
These smells.
會是那里嗎
Could it be?
真不敢相信我居然答應來了
Can't believe I said yes to this.
我覺得最好抓住每次機會
I think it's best to say yes whenever possible.
你覺得呢
Don't you think?
好吧
Okay.
不知道城里的狗會不會喜歡這地方
Well, I wonder what a city dog's gonna make of this place.
農場  我回來了
The farm! I'm back!
我們去看看吧
Should we check it out?
我聞到馬狗了
I smell horse-dogs!
我聞到漢娜了  我聞到我的男孩了
I smell Hannah! I smell my boy!
你好
Hello.
你是從哪來的
Where'd you come from?
伊森  是我
Ethan, it's me!
我是貝利  貝利  貝利  貝利
It's Bailey, Bailey, Bailey, Bailey.
伊森  外面怎么了
Ethan, wh-what's going on out here?
-怎么...  -你看啊
- What...? - Look at this.
你真是個小可愛
Aren't you a cutie pie?
你的主人是誰
Who is your owner?
我想...
I think...
你可能是我奶奶  漢娜
you might be my Grandma Hannah?
我是
I am.
CJ
CJ?
天吶  這個地方感覺很熟悉
God, I feel like I know this place.
當然了
Of course you do.
這是你家
It's home.
CJ
CJ?
你長大了
Y-You grew up.
這是你的狗嗎
I-Is that... is that your dog?
是的  這是麥克斯
Yeah, that's, um... this is Max.
小心  他不是很友好
Be careful. He's not very friendly.
是啊  你是個殺手
Yeah, you're a killer.
好吧
Okay.
我照你說的做了  伊森
I did what you told me, Ethan.
很不容易  花了很長時間  但我做到了
It was not easy. It took a long time, but I did it.
我把CJ帶回家了
I brought CJ home.
你好
Hello.
Hi.
很高興認識你們
Nice to meet you.
-天吶  -真漂亮  你看
- My gosh. - Oh, that's beautiful. Look at that.
你看這張
Look at this one.
你們兩個認識多久了
So, how long have you two known each other?
從十歲起我們就是最好的朋友
Best friends since we were ten years old.
那你們不是...
So, you're not, uh...
不是  不是
No. No.
我們只是朋友
We're, um... we're just friends.
天吶  我看起來好開心
Gosh, I look so happy.
為什么我媽媽不讓我見你們
Why did my mother keep me away from you?
你爸爸去世時  格洛麗亞年紀很小
When your father died, Gloria was so young,
我覺得她認為全世界都在跟她作對
and I think she thought that the world was against her.
她不明白我們是站在她那邊的
And she couldn't see that we were on her side.
對嗎
Right?
我再去拿幾本相冊來
I'm gonna get some more photo albums.
貝利交給你
Here. Take Bailey.
他叫麥克斯
His-his name's Max.
好吧  麥克斯
Okay... Max.
他真正的名字叫貝利
You know, his real name is Bailey.
對吧  狗老大
Ain't that right, Boss Dog?
沒錯
That's right.
我喜歡聽他叫我"狗老大"
I love when he calls me "Boss Dog."
我唯一想不通的是
The only thing I can't figure
狗老大怎么會變得這么嬌小
is how Boss Dog can be such a little guy.
等等  你是說我的狗其實是你的狗
Wait, so, my dog is actually your dog?
我把他永久租借
He's on permanent loan.
給你了
To you.
好吧
Okay.
貝利是伊森小時候的狗
Bailey was Ethan's dog when he was a kid,
他總是說貝利變成別的狗回來了
and he always said that Bailey came back as a different dog
讓我們在分開多年后重新走到一起
and brought us back together after many years apart.
現在他認為麥克斯就是貝利
And now he thinks that Max is Bailey
貝利讓你回到了我們身邊
and Bailey's brought you to us.
她認為我老糊涂了
She thinks I lost my marbles.
這個嘛
Oh, well...
你就是這么想的
Yeah, you do.
-這件事上我很肯定  -好吧
- I know what I'm talking about on this one. - Sure.
你也不相信我  對嗎CJ
You don't believe me, either, CJ, do you?
關于那條狗  你還有很多不知道的
There's a lot you don't know about that dog.
我可以證明給你看
I could show you.
-來吧  貝利  -來了
- Come on, Bailey. - Coming.
好吧
Okay.
我很久沒做過這個了
Yeah, it's been a while since I've done this.
我曾經是站著做的
I used to do it standing up.
好了  你...
All right, you...
準備好了嗎
Okay, you ready?
我們像以前那樣做吧
Let's do it just like we used to.
好
Okay.
一
One.
二
Two.
三
Three.
上
Go!
這東西什么時候變得這么大了
When did this thing get so big?
很厲害吧
Pr-Pretty great, right?
什么
Wha...?
只不過現在...
Only... only now the...
橄欖球比他還重
The football weighs more than he does.
等等
Wait.
-他怎么...  -我也不明白為什么
- How did... - I don't know how or what.
貝利臨死前
When Bailey died,
我讓他照顧你
I told him to take care of you.
保護你
To protect you.
我相信他做到了
And I believe that's what he did.
對不對  狗老大
Ain't that right, Boss Dog?
終于想明白時  感覺有點奇怪吧
It's kind of weird when you finally get it, right?
特倫特
Trent?
Trent!
他在那邊
He's over there.
我得走了  伊森
I got to go, Ethan.
你讓我保護她的
You told me to protect her.
特倫特  特倫特
Trent. Trent!
怎么了  出什么事了
Wh-What is it? What's wrong?
沒什么
Nothing.
沒出事
Nothing's wrong.
特倫特  麥克斯就是莫莉
Max was Molly, Trent.
所以他能聞出你病了
That's how he knew you were sick.
-什么  -麥克斯就是莫莉
- What? - Max was Molly.
在莫莉之前  他是伊森的狗  貝利
And before Molly, he was Ethan's dog, Bailey.
我覺得大狗也是他
And I think he was also Big Dog,
他跟我握爪  還幫我贏了五十美元
who gave me its paw and helped me win 50 dollars.
好吧
Okay.
麥克斯讓我們走到了一起  特倫特
Max brought us together, Trent.
他找到了我  然后又找到了你
He found me, and then he found you,
然后他救了你的命
and then he saved your life.
這一切都是為了讓我們在一起
All so we could be together.
拜托
Come on.
你們能趕緊舔臉嗎
Would you just lick faces already?
這可能嗎
Is it possible?
不
No.
完全不可能
No, it's utterly impossible.
但我想這是真的
But I guess it's true.
我愛你  特倫特
I love you, Trent.
我一直愛著你
I've always loved you.
我愛了你一輩子了
I've loved you forever.
終于
Finally.
謝謝你  麥克斯
Thank you, Max.
還有莫莉
And Molly.
還有貝利  還有大狗
And Bailey, and Big Dog.
那些都是我
Those are all me.
是啊
Yeah.
我照伊森說的做了
I did what Ethan asked.
家書
克拉里蒂·瓊
我照顧CJ  讓她過上好日子
I watched after CJ so that she would have a good life,
有個好家庭
with a good pack.
看起來很棒
It looks great.
想聽聽我寫的關于你的歌嗎  麥克斯
You want to hear a song I wrote about you, Max?
CJ叫我的名字  我永遠都聽不厭
I never got tired of hearing CJ say my name.
我活了很多次
I had a lot of lives.
每次都不同
All different.
有時候高大
Sometimes I was big,
有時候嬌小
and sometimes I was small.
媽媽抱
Here's Mama.
你好嗎
How you doing?
親一下
Kiss.
我們去看狗
Let's go see the dog.
那么多起起落落
So many ups and downs.
-格洛麗亞偶爾也會出現了  -真好
- Even Gloria came around once in a while. - Yes.
我訓練她玩耍
I trained her to play.
對  那是小狗
Yeah. That's the puppy.
那么多道別
So many good-byes.
我離開了那么多次  每次他都在我身邊
He'd been with me so many times when I had to leave.
這次有我在他身邊
Now I got to be with him.
我們將伊森·蒙哥馬利交由您照護
We release Ethan Montgomery into your care.
原主祝福你  保佑你
May the Lord bless you and keep you.
愿主的光輝照耀你  賜予你平靜...
May the Lord's face shine upon you and give you peace...
蒙哥馬利
詹姆斯  多蘿西
伊森
那么多人
So many people.
一路走過  我讓我愛的人
Through it all, I let the people I loved
知道我有多愛他們
know just how much I loved them.
他怎么樣了
How's he doing?
他躺了一整天了
He's just been lying there all day.
你是個好孩子  麥克斯
You're a good boy, Max.
最好的
The best.
沒有你我們該怎么辦
Where would we be without you?
你是條好狗  莫莉·麥克斯
You're a good dog, Molly Max.
你真是條好狗
You're such a good dog.
躺在我的女孩的懷里
Lying there with my girl holding me,
我能感覺到時候又到了
I can feel it happening again.
我知道我要道別了
I knew I was saying good-bye,
但我并不傷感
but I wasn't sad.
? 親近或遙遠 ?
♪ Near or far ♪
? 結束或開始 ?
♪ The end or the start ♪
? 我都會 ?
♪ I'll be here ♪
? 陪著你 ?
♪ With you ♪
? 我都會 ?
♪ I'll be here ♪
? 陪著你 ?
♪ With you. ♪
我知道這是真的
I knew this to be true.
我的名字叫貝利
My name was Bailey.
還有莫莉  大狗  麥克斯
And Molly, and Big Dog, and Max.
我是條好狗  狗老大
I was a good dog, a Boss Dog.
我知道愛人類是我的終極使命
I knew that loving people was my ultimate purpose.
而現在來到這里
And that being here now,
永遠愛他們  就是我的獎賞
loving them forever was my reward.
你好  狗老大
Hello, Boss Dog.
來吧  孩子
Come on, boy.
來吧  伙計
Come on. Come on, buddy.
準備好了嗎
All right. Ready?
好了嗎  上
Ready? Go!
干得好  狗老大
Way to go, Boss Dog!
一條狗的使命2